[music]
[bell]
[bell and music]
Heat. Heat.
[bell]
[music]
>> [music]
>> Hello everybody. Good evening and good
day to everyone and welcome back to the
Ask Abijit show. I hope you're all doing
great. Today we discuss history. We
discuss world and Indian history and I
have selected a large number of
questions that you have asked in the
comments and I'll take as many of those
as possible today. Before we do that as
always let us see who all is there on
the live chat. I can see Krishna Su
Krishna of the Surinam Netherlands.
Vicash PJ namaste Sukun Vatcher hello
tst 67 GK GS1K crazy brain hello
geopolitical Dubai is here from Indor
good evening animals for laugh is here
from Mumbai real painter all hail to you
as well is here from Jaipur vidi manar
thank you ma'am good to see you um Tmay
Pande uh TS okay G gkgs okay Vikash PJ J
Sa Sanduji from Chandigar. Hello. A real
painter is here. [laughter]
Um who else? Sumit Agarwal Ram Sumit
Mahul Rajes Babu Swami M A K4J
Ankita Kachab is here. Good evening.
Rocket Rocket EJ Adwit Ashwani Aush
Singh is here. Pam Pam uh Sagar G is
here from Bangalore. Bangaluru Om Nyak
is here. Tanmay once again. Event
countdown 1 to three. Hello Manisha.
Namaste. Namaste. Daam da nam Priya
Priyadashi. Okay, good to see you. Um
Vikas PJ Sukum Verer. Who else do we
have? Surajit Achara is here.
Uh Nutan Roshan.
Uh Somia Paul.
Somalia Paul from West Bengal. Um,
who else? Who else? Uh, Arian Rocking
Gaming 6950. Nutan Roshan. Namaskarum.
Uh, Surajit Achara Om Nikk Red John03.
Good to see you. Raj John 03 and
everybody else. So, I'm streaming I'm
trying an experiment streaming in two
different aspect ratios. uh if you are
used to the uh you know the horizontal
one you can see in that one. If you want
to see on a cell phone then you can see
the vertical one. It's up to you. It's
not like I'm forcing one aspect ratio on
everybody. We have two aspect ratios
being streamed on at the same time on
YouTube and I'm also streaming on
Twitter and wherever else Facebook link
LinkedIn and um kick etc. Twitch and so
on. Okay. So let us go with let's get
going with the questions. What questions
do we have? All right. Let us go. Let
what questions? Let me quickly check the
questions. Here we go. What is the first
question that we have today? And that is
by Amisha Mishra. Do you agree that the
term South Asian was invented to erase
the legacy and history of what has for
centuries been known as Indian
civilization? See the term South Asia
was invented by the US State Department.
At least it was popularized and brought
into the mainstream by the US state
department. Maybe the term was used
before that but it's when the state
department starts pushing it somewhere
in the 1950s 1960s onwards that the term
south asia becomes commonplace and today
Indians use the term south Asia without
understanding what it means. We even
have the sark south Asian association
for regional cooperation. Why do we have
to you know accept this term south asia?
So why has this term being in been
invented and what's what is the point of
it all? So if you want to understand
that let me put this image on screen
that will explain in very in great
clarity what what this what the
intention of this is and and I don't
take credit for this uh this graphic it
is credit where it is due it is it was
created by somebody called strider eel
so this is a strategic guide on the
usage of the term south Asia and western
media in academia and so on this is more
about western media so what kind of news
do we have? If it is good news, okay,
and the country of origin of the good
news is Pakistan, then the western media
will use the term Pakistan. They will
not say South Asia. If there is good
news, but it's coming from India, they
will use the term South Asia, not India.
If there is bad news that's coming out
of Pakistan, they will say South Asia,
not Pakistan. And if there is bad news
coming out of India, then they will say
India, not South Asia. So South Asia is
is used to erase the existence of India
when there is something good that you
want to speak about that comes out from
the subcontinent Indian subcontinent
right and if there's something bad
that's happening then you use the term
term South Asia for example in in the UK
you have these Pakistani gangs who pray
on girls and women right
and that's a well-known scandal I don't
know how many tens of thousands maybe
hundreds of thousands of girls have been
victimized by these Pakistan
monsters. So what term do they use for
this? They use the term Asian gangs or
maybe South Asian gangs. They never use
the term Pakistani gangs,
right? So they want to make people
believe that even Indians are included
in this when something bad is going on.
So when something bad happens, use the
term South Asia. Don't use the term
Pakistan even though most bad things
come out of Pakistan. And when something
good is going on which is coming from
Pakistan then don't use the term South
Asia. Use Pakistan. When something good
happens from India, use the term South
Asia to include everybody else. Even
when it comes to history,
the history of the subcontinent is
Indian history. It's not Pakistani
history or Bangladeshi history. It's
Indian history. The entire subcontinent
was India before the 1940s. Right? But
once again to erase the Indian identity
of our history and civilization they use
the term South Asia. So it is a
deliberate ploy
to erase
our history our culture our civilization
and uh whenever something bad happens
that comes from India they lose India
otherwise they use the term South Asia
and so on. So that is why they're doing
it and so what should we do about this?
What we should do is we should reject
the term South Asia. Stop using the term
South Asia. Use the term Indian
subcontinent.
That is the correct term. The term
Indian subcontinent includes all of what
they call South Asia, right? Pakistan,
Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Nepal, Bhutan,
um Sri Lanka, Maldives. It could it can
also include Burma and Persia depending
on how you want to use it. But uh if you
want to exclude Burma and Persia that's
fine but the rest of the subcontinent
is part of that. So use the term Indian
subcontinent never use the term South
Asia. All right great question.
Next question is by Shub and Subjit
Karmakar.
Why did Persians never try to invade
India? Was it because of a cultural
reason or or because of powerful Indian
empires? Uh did they lack the strategy
of fighting against Indian war
elephants? And Shojit says the more I
study about Persia and its link with
ancient India, the more it feels like an
extension of the western Indian
population like Gujarati Hindi Baloji.
DNA is similar, language is pretty
close. Even the surnames uh end in
similar tones. If that's the case, did
Bharatwash actually stretch from Persia
to Bengal and the Palmir to Sri Lanka?
Maybe Persia with time came to became
too big in its own right to be called
just an extension. If that's the case,
what prevented other distant parts like
Bengal, Tamil Nadu, etc. from becoming
separate cultural entities during the
same time period? Okay. So, what's the
deal with Persia?
Is it an extension of India? Is it was
it actually part of Batwash? Did Barhat
wor stretch from Persia to to Bengal and
Palmer to Sri Lanka? Is that the case?
Well, [snorts] what is the origin of
Persia? That's what we view to ask
ourselves. What's the origin? Now, if
you study your standard history
textbooks, the colonial history
textbooks, which even today when it
comes to dealing with Indian history,
they they have all these colonial
baggage that they carry. The Arian
invasion theory which is now, you know,
transformed into an Arian migration
theory. But the the the same premise,
right? So according to that theory there
was that Indian you know the Indian and
Iranian people they had the same
ancestry and then they were part of the
arian invaders one branch split off and
went into Iran and one branch split off
and came into the subcontinent that's
the story so even the colonial
um version of history will tell you that
India and Persia have the same ancestors
and same original uh history. Now the
truth is that there was no arian
invasion on migration or tourism or
picnic that's a lie in that's that's
going to be debunked and um I have
spoken in detail about that so I will
not go into that
the origin of Persia can be understood
when you study the riga and one episode
or one one event that's mentioned in the
rigida which is the battle of the 10
kings the battle of the 10 kings and
king sudas wins the battle against more
than 10 kings who are arrayed against
him and the losing confederation of
kings and and clans are expelled out of
India. They are expelled exiled
permanently out of India. They go
westwards and northwards out of India.
And one of the clans was the Parhua
clan. Para and that name comes from the
battle axe which is called Pu in
Sanskrit. So the Pawa clan went
westwards and settled in what is now
Persia. And the name Persia comes from
the Para clan, the name of the clan
itself.
So Persia in from that perspective is a
is a daughter civilization of India. So
the parhas were they went out of India.
They settled in what is now Persia and
eventually um they became a civilization
in their own right a pretty robust
civilization a pretty great civilization
right um and that's why you will find
that there is obviously a very clear
linkages there are clear linkages
between India and Persia u but see
understand this that the Persian
population of today if you see the
Persian people today they will be
nothing like the Persian people, the
Persian population that existed around
500 AD.
In 500 AD,
the the Persians had not lost their
sovereignty yet. They had not been
invaded and overrun by the Arabs and
then by the Seljuks, the Turks and so
on. So they were still sovereign and
because of that
foreign populations had not been settled
in Persia. So the original true Persians
of 500 AD
they don't look like the Persians of
today. If you go to Persia today you
will find lots of Persians who look
almost like Europeans.
These are the descendants of people who
were brought in by the Turks from the
Caucasus region and settled in Persia.
You'll find lots of Persians who look
more Turk smaller eyes and that's sort
of those those those features right
that's because tremendous amount of
Turks a tremendous number of Turks were
settled in Persia by the Turk occupiers
of Persia the Turks ruled Persia for
roughly a thousand years right before
that it was the Arabs who ruled Persia
for several centuries so the population
has been significantly transformed
today
but the original Persians of around 500
BC they would have looked very much like
the people of western India Balojasthan
sind the gujarat and so on they would
have looked very much like the people of
these parts of the subcontinent so that
is one thing we to understand today's
Persians are kind of different the
original Persians they will still look
like people from western India but lots
of persons lots of Iranians today look
more like people from the cauasus region
or maybe like Turks so That's one thing
we have to keep in mind. Now
so that we now that now that we
understand that what about Persia never
trying to invade India. See the Persian
Empire especially the Aminid Empire the
Hakamanish Empire was an extremely
militaristic empire an expansionist
empire. They constantly fought against
the Greeks and eventually with the
Romans. They they conquered Mesopotamia.
They conquered Egypt.
Right? They fought the Greeks
continuously, relentlessly. They even
fought the Romans, the Persians did.
So if they were so powerful,
if they were an expansionist empire, why
on earth did they never bother to expand
eastwards into India? See,
Persia and India had a common border.
Okay? And that border changed from time
to time. See when India became
fragmented when when India was unified
under a single empire like the Morian
Empire and so on then the border would
shift westwards because India was more
powerful but when India was fragmented
then the border would shift slightly
eastwards when the Persians would take
small bites of territory that is a
natural process and there's going to be
some border tensions low-level tensions
but there was never a Persian invasion
of India border skirmishes and all those
things they happen between any two
neighbor neighbors
So there were times when the Persian
India Persia border was at the Synindhu
river, the Indust. There were times when
it was further west, significantly
further west from the indust. There were
times when Gandhar was was part of the
Akimerid Empire. There were times when
Gandhar was with us historically. It was
ours.
But why did Persia never bother to
invade India? Why did they never even
draw plans to launch an invasion of
India? That is a big question. And
that's another big question that no
historian has bothered to answer.
And
to understand the reasons why, let us
revisit a period, you know, a small
episode of history that happened after
Persia was overrun by the Arabs. So
after the Persians were overrun by the
Arabs,
the Persians composed a poem. See when
the Persians when the Arabs conquered
Persia at that time
in India the Gupta Empire had
essentially disintegrated and there was
a period of time for several centuries
where where India was not unified under
a single empire. India was a collection
of kingdoms at this time. It's a
cyclical process. So because India was
no longer unified under a single empire.
India could not help the Persians.
And when the Arabs invaded and conquered
Persia, the Persians wrote this poem.
Let me put this on the screen. Okay,
it's called the ballad the ballad of
King Vaham and it has you know you'll
find multiple versions of this. Let me
put this on the screen. So if you want
the actual uh if you want an actual
research paper this is the one. Okay,
it's by JC Tawadia. It's from 1955
Journal of the Royal Asiatic Society of
Great Britain in Ireland. And this
gentleman writes about this this uh you
know rhymed ballad in the Pali language.
Okay. And what's it say?
Um it says when may it be that the kurer
comes from India and says that the
shaharam from the family of the kais has
come that there are a thousand elephants
upon their heads are elephant keepers
and that he wrote holds the raised
standard in the manner of the hostas
that the advanced guard is led by army
chiefs and intelligent man should be
made our clever interpreter who may go
and speak to the Indians. What have we
seen from the hand of the Arabs? They
ruined the religion and killed. They
ruined our religion and killed our
kings. We are from the Aryan race and
they are like demons the Arabs. They
have taken away the sovereignty from the
hosteras. Not by skill, not by manliness
but by you know mockery and scorn. They
have taken away by force from men, wives
and wealth, palaces, parks, gardens and
so much more. Okay. Now this is a let me
show you a different translation. It
says when will a kura come from India to
say that king vaham of the family of the
kawi has come upon elephants and you
know to to to rescue Persia and a man
should be dispatched a clever
interpreter who may go and tell to India
what has happened to us at the hands of
the Arabs they've destroyed our religion
and killed our kings and so on so the
Persians wish clearly
from this poem it's clear that they wish
that India would come and rescue
And they they they wish that they could
send an interpreter
or a messenger to the Indians who could
tell the Indians what has happened in
Persia, what horrors have befallen
Persia and maybe the Indians could come
and help us. And King Vaharam from the
from the family of the Kavis will come
from India. What does that tell you?
That a Persian king from the family of
the Kavis will come from India. What
does it tell you? It means the Persians
regarded Indians as their kin, as their
family, as the same race and blood. Do
you understand what that means? It means
Persia and India were always
kin. They were we were sister
civilizations, you could say, or
daughter, mother, whatever you want to
call it. But the Persians did not regard
Indians as as foreigners. And when you
come upon the worst times in your life,
who who do you ask for help? Do you ask
strangers for help? No, you ask your
closest relatives for help. So that is
the tragedy of what happened in Persia.
And they wish that Indians could come
and help them. But India at that time
was fragmented. We did not have a single
empire. In case we did, perhaps our
emperor could have come and help. We
could have gone and helped the Persians.
But at that time India was fragmented.
The Gupta Empire had ended because of
the Hunik invasions, relentless Hunic
invasions. And that's what happened.
So why did the Persians never try to
invade India? Because we were family.
They saw us as their kin.
They saw us as their own people. And I
suppose we would have seen the Persians
as our own pe our own people too. And
there seems to have been some kind of
understanding between India and Persia.
We won't fight each other. We may have
some border disputes. We may have some
disagreements, smallcale disagreements
about the line of the border where it
should be and all. That's a different
story. But I will not invade you. you
will not invade me. We may have
disagreements but we will resolve them
in a civilized manner. That was the
deal. Right? So the Persians did not
attempt to invade India because they
were scared of India because you know
because the Indian war elephants were
very scary or whatever. It was some kind
of cultural civilizational
blood level understanding that we won't
fight each other. And that's something
we can't imagine today. If you look at
Persia today, they look today many
Persians look very foreign to Indians,
right? The language also is
incomprehensible almost. The language is
actually very comprehensible. You spend
a couple of weeks in Persia, you'll
start speaking Persian. If you are
someone who speaks
so a so-called Indo-arian language,
it'll be very easy to pick up Persian. I
when I was a student I knew Persians who
were you know people from students from
Iran who were studying in India and they
spoke Hindi fluently they just picked it
up the two languages are very very
similar the roots are very similar
so that's the deal about Persia
subjit says hypothetically wouldn't it
have been better if the ancient Indians
pushed beyond Gandhar into Persia and
controlled the Zagros mountains given
that Persia was our sister civilization,
daughter's civilization, whatever you
want to call it and culturally not very
different from us and stopping invasions
of the Zagros mountains would have been
easier instead of the Kyber past. The
Arabs were able to reach India so
rapidly because the Persians failed to
defend the Zagros mountains. Okay. So
what's the deal? What should India have
done? First of all, let's ask ourselves
where is where are the so-called these
these Zagros mountains? So, let's take a
look at the map and let's
determine where these mountains lie. So,
let's just ask the map. Zagros [snorts]
mountain range. There we go. So, it's
going to be in western Iran. There we
have it. As you can see, it's
highlighted over here. It's in western
Persia, Western Iran, the Zagros
mountains. And when the Arabs invaded
Persia, they came through this region.
They did not come by sea. They came by
land and they had to cross the Zagros
mountains and uh they were able to do
that successfully and they conquered
Iran and Persia and transformed it
forever. Right? Persia has never come
back from what happened. It lost its
sovereignty and the sovereignty never
really returned culturally and
civilizationally. The culture and
civilization were erased. That's what
happened. So would it not have been
better for India
to have pushed beyond Gandhar and and
taken over Persia and control the Zagros
mountains right
did it make sense for us to do that so
two things first of all like I discussed
in the previous question India and
Persia had had an understanding we won't
fight each other I won't invade you you
won't invade me and that's it we are the
same people we fight each other. We'll
fight them lectures, the barbarians, the
Greeks and the Romans and the Egyptians
and the Mesopotamians and all. That's
what the Persians did. And our people
were happy in the subcontinent gigantic
land mass. We don't need to go beyond
that. So why why fight our own people?
That sort of thing. So India and Persia
never fought each other in any
significant way beyond
minor border disagreements or whatever
which never led to a war, a full-scale
war. maybe some small clashes here and
there that is natural even among Indian
kingdoms used to it used to happen but
never a full-scale invasion so that's
why India never invaded Persia secondly
how would the rulers of India know that
something has emerged out of out of
Arabia that would very rapidly take over
Persia and then attempt to invade India
see when the Mongols suddenly erupted
from Mongolia under Shri Chingghist Khan
the Chinese initially did not take them
seriously. Why? Because nothing had ever
come out of Mongolia that had any
serious consequences. Mongolia was
forever a land of small tribes that
constantly fought each other. So the
Chinese never imagined that the Mongols
would suddenly unite under one person
and they would become the greatest
conquering force of all time until that
time.
Similarly,
the Arabs were pretty similar. They came
from a land where almost nothing was
there, nothing grew, uh, a desert land.
And they they themselves were these
small tribes.
They were a polytheistic culture. And,
uh, those days you did not have social
media and TV and journalists and
whatever. So, you did not know what was
happening in Arabia.
And let's say you find out that this new
this new religion has come from Arabia,
you won't take it seriously, right? And
the Arabs had never conquered anybody
until this point in time. So the Indians
would never have imagined, our ancestors
would never have imagined that something
monumental would emerge out of a out of
Arabia and very rapidly conquer Persia
and then start knocking at our doorstep
and trying to conquer us.
So multiple reasons why India did not do
this. Firstly, we had this understanding
we will never fight each other, India
and Persia. Secondly, nobody had any
idea of something monumental that's
going to erupt out of Arabia and conquer
Persia and then eventually seek to
conquer India. These are the reasons why
uh none of these things happened.
Feline lover says, "Why are all
Indo-Iranian people of Central Asia
classified as irranic specifically
Eastern Iranic when they seem either
when they either seem to be equally
close to Indians and Iranians or closer
to Indians? Even modern eastern Iranic
like pashons are genetically closest to
northwestern Indians. Do you think
eastern Iranic is a misnomer? See
there's this
there's this there's there has been this
concerted effort in the west. See today
who has written our history. It's the
westerners who have written our history.
They have written the histories of the
world of the of the countries of the
world when it comes to the history of
Persia. They will draw upon Persian
sources but they will come to their to
their own conclusions. So the history of
the world the way we read it the way we
are taught it is written by westerners.
Now for the west India was a
civilization to be destroyed.
that that attempt is still going on to
destroy India civilization, culture,
etc. It's still ongoing. So when they
see us as a civilization to be destroyed
because they want to make the entire
world a monotheistic place, right?
In that case, you have to erase Indian
history. You have to erase any science
of Indian greatness
and you you have to justify your
destruction of India. Right? Because the
British ruled India for two and a half
centuries. They had to justify the
destructure of India.
So what do you do to justify that? You
portray the Indians as barbaric savages,
backward, primitive people who have all
these horrible problems in society and
they deserve to be ruled by by white
people. That's what you have to portray
India as. So you have to you have to
erase any aspect of Indian history that
that shows that India was great.
Now it's known that Indians in ancient
times did venture out into Central Asia
and various parts of the world and
settle these places
for for example
before the Turkification Islamization of
Central Asia. Central Asia was Hindu
Buddhist all of it. You still have
stupas in Turk Manistan and Kazakhstan
and whatn not all across central Asia
even in so-called singang
even in Armenia you will find Hindu
temples that were repurposed into
churches who have now those have now
been repurp repurposed in Araasak etc
into mosques
you will find
statues of of Bhagan Vishnu you'll find
them in in Russia so Indians were spread
all across central Asia and Indians
established kingdoms and dynasties in
central Asia and these eventually
intermingled with local peoples and
maybe the the genetic makeup became
mixed but these were still culturally
Indian
so to deny India's greatness to justify
your destruction of India and your
plunder of India you have to deny these
things so what do you do you classify
all these various central Asian peoples
as irranic not India Indian the skitians
the shakas irranic
the pashons irranic everything ironic
nothing Indian you don't you deny any
presence of India anywhere India was a
backward
poor you know society nothing great ever
came out of India that's how you justify
your rule over India and that attitude
has continued even after the British
British Raj ended because the British
Raj has never ended. The British Empire
has simply transformed into a different
entity which is the American Empire
and the the same
the same uh thought process continues
and uh they still seek to subjugate
India. They still seek to destroy Indian
civilization that pro that those efforts
are ongoing right now on India's soil.
Right?
So that is the reason why uh you have
what you have described here. The
central Asian peoples are all described
as irranic. The skits are described as
irranic. The pons are described as Iran.
The pashons are an extension of the
northern Indian population but
genetically and culturally very clearly
so but they'll be described as irranic.
Next,
Amisha says, "Why does Turkey deny the
Armenian genocide so vehemently when the
genocide was done by the Ottomans, not
by the current Turkish state?"
Oh, first of all, this is a horrible
topic, okay? The Armenian genocide was
not one event. It was multiple events.
There were at least three different
waves
of ar of the Armenian genocide starting
in the last quarter of the 19th century
and it culminated around 1915
when the triumvirate
of Anar Talat Talat and Jamal the three
Pashas the young Turks they decided to
exterminate the Armenians from what is
Turkey currently now Turkey Anatolia and
so
And um
so this was a horrific event and a
horrific series of events. Um so the
first phases in the in the late 19th
century of the Armenian genocide
happened under Ottoman rule. But the
culmination of the Armenian genocide
happened during the rule of the three
parashas the young Turks
Anwar, Talat, Talat and Jabal.
So that was not the Ottoman Empire. And
beyond that, it's not just the Armenian
genocide. There's been a Pontic
genocide. The indigenous Greeks who
resided in what is currently Turkey,
they were genocided,
right? It's it's a long story. We cannot
go into all the details today. The
question is these events did happen. The
genocides did happen,
right? So why does Turkey deny that this
happened? Because it was done by the
Ottomans and then by the young Turks by
the by the triumphirate of Anatal Jamal
Jamal. What does it have to do with
today's Turkey? Right? That's the
question you're asking. Well, you see
today's Turkey is is a continuation of
all those eras.
And so after the triumvirate period of
alatar
jamal you had a brief period of foreign
occupation then you had the Turkish war
of independence which was won by Shri
Mustafa Kimal Ataturk and that's when
the modern nation of Turkey was founded.
Ataturk saved Turkey. He freed it from
foreign occupation and he ruled as a
dictator for until 1938 or something.
You can look it up.
the exact years
and after's
death you had the continuation of Turkey
and you had multiple dictatorships all
of those governments you had periods of
military rule and so on and they all
claim to be continuing what Ataturk
started
now today you have Erdogan right
Erdogan who seeks to undo whatever
Ataturk did and go back to the time of
the Ottoman Empire. He seeks to relamize
Turkey because Ataturk
tried his best to
essentially
erase Islam from Turkey. He turned he
transformed Turkey into a secular nation
by force.
He changed the day of the holiday from
Friday to Sunday. He said that no women
will wear a veil and so on. He did so
many many of these reforms. And today
Turkey is going back to its Ottoman
heritage. They're kind of the young
younger Turkish people are beginning to
turn their back on the reforms of
Ataturk. The older Turkish people, they
are still secular. So Turkey is
reverting to its to its Ottoman roots
and
Erdogan seeks to create a neotoman
empire of sorts. So when Turkey is
clearly identifying with its Ottoman
heritage and the Ottomans did this
barbaric thing and the later government
also well Turkey will deny that right
and the the thing is there will be lots
of Turks who privately extol and glorify
the genocide.
There was another event the burning of
Smyrna. There's a city called Smyrna
in Anatolia which is now called Ismir.
So that city was burned. The Greek,
Armenian, Christian, etc. Jewish
quarters were burned by the Turks and
lots of people obviously died and the
Turks like to make fun of the Greeks
saying that you know you guys swim very
well. That's why you survived.
You great swimmers you Greeks. So, so
privately the Turks
they they celebrate the genocides
they they glorify the genociders
but and that's why publicly so they
identify with what happened they are
proud of what happened privately and
publicly that's why they will say that
this never happened the genocide never
happened so that's the deal the
genocides did happen
the Pontic genocide the the Armenian
genocide and god knows what else the
Turks
Absolute brutal barbarity.
Right.
Okay. A couple of questions. Seroni
Mishra says, "Why was Zoroastrianism
almost wiped out by Islam but Hinduism
wasn't?" Vijit Shira Rajan says, "From
what I gather, Dharma seems to have
declined rapidly in Gandhar and Kashmir.
Soon after the arrival of foreign
rulers, but didn't decline quite as
severely in the other parts of northern
and western India. What was the
different in Gandhar and Kashmir?
Let me address the second one first.
Dharma did not decline in Kashmir. It
declined in Gandhar rapidly. Kashmir it
took a long long time for Dharma to
decline. Okay.
Now coming to Salon's question. Why was
Zoroastrianism wiped out rapidly very
rapidly by Islam but Hinduism did not?
You see what is the thing that we call
Hinduism?
It's the oldest known religious,
cultural, civilizational practice in the
world that still exists, right? It's
thousands of years old and it has
absorbed all kinds of local folk
traditions. Everything has been absorbed
into it and it's part of Hinduism. So if
you look at the way our ancestors
practiced what we call Hinduism in
different parts of India, the practices
were very different.
They would they would worship local
gods, local goddesses, folk deities,
nature deities,
rivers, mountains, hills, trees,
ancestors,
pitrus,
all kinds of local traditions were
combined into Hinduism of tremendously
diverse, tremendously plural religion,
if you want to call it a religion,
right? And those traditions came back
from thousands of years before, maybe
tens of thousands of years. So these
were very ancient practices. And
Hinduism doesn't have this pyramidal
military style command and control
structure where you if you do a
decapitation strike at the very top,
everything crumbles. It's not like that.
Hinduism is completely decentralized.
There is no pope in Hinduism.
There is no cardinal. There no there are
no priests. There are I mean priests,
pundits and all we have but we don't
have bishops and cardinals and popes and
all that. So if you take out that
leadership portion everything else just
crumbles and collapses. It's not the
case. And people held on to their their
their heritage, their culture, their
their ancestral [clears throat]
customs because those came back thousand
went back thousands of years.
So these are some of the reasons why
Hinduism could not be wiped out uh by
the Turks. Even though they tried, they
tried their best. It was not from for a
lack of trying that they were not able
to in convert the Indian subcontinent.
But as we know what is now Pak I mean
you know what is now Pakistan,
Bangladesh that's almost exclusively
Islamic now. Afghanistan which was
historically Gandhar is almost
exclusively like 99.99% Islamic today.
So these things happen right? So there
was success but today even if you look
at the overall population of the
subcontinent it's still majority Hindu
at least nominally. I'm not sure how
many Indians today in India actually
practice Hinduism. Some of them are
Hindus only in name. Some of them have
have converted to some foreign religion
quietly secretly and yeah Hinduism is is
you know the way things are going it
will be extinct soon 50 years 100 years
maximum if we don't change course but
that's a different story. We will not go
into that right now.
So that's why Hinduism because of its
incredible antiquity because people were
practicing these traditions for
thousands of years. They didn't want to
give them up because we did not have
this top- down structure. If you take
out the leadership top leadership
everything else collapses and because of
the incredible decentralization and plur
plurality of Hinduism that's why
Hinduism could not be wiped out. also
because of the vernati system which
acted as a preserver. The vernati system
acted as a preserver and and savior of
Hinduism. Okay, you may call it evil or
whatever cast system you may call it.
It's not a cast system. It's a verata
system. It's a totally different thing.
It's an organization of a
self-organizing society which every
every so society has. So that's why
Hinduism could not be wiped out. What
about zoroastrianism?
Well, you see, Zoroastrinism,
it emerged, we don't quite know when it
emerged, maybe around 700 BC or
somewhere around that time.
Probably after Kurush,
Kurush, Cyrus, Cyrus the Great. His name
was actually actual name was Kurush.
Kurush Vajarak Vajarak. So uh most
likely it is after the ru the reign of
kurush that zoroastrianism emerged.
That's the consensus today. We're not
I'm not quite sure if it's true but
let's assume that's around that time
that zoroastrianism emerges. Ratasra is
born and he brings about this new
religion maybe around 600 700 AD uh BC
around that time. So what was this new
religion zoroastrinism? It was a
polytheistic revolt against Hinduism.
See before Zar Zaratustra,
Persia had only one religion and culture
which was Hinduism. Okay, the old Vic
religion. Let's ask Google if Google
agrees.
Let's ask Google if many people will
disagree and Google may disagree. But
let's see. Okay. Uh, what was the pre
the pre zoroastrian
religion of Persia?
Let's see what it says. Okay, this is
going to be fun. The priestan religion
of Persia was the ancient Indo-Iranian
religion, a polytheistic and shamanistic
faith that shared many similarities with
the Vic religion. [laughter]
Okay. So it is indirectly telling you
that it was Hinduism pre Iranian indo
what the old Indo-Iranian religion
shamanistic and polytheistic what what
on earth is that
the old Indo-Iranian religion was
Hinduism vic Hinduism so Persia was
Hindu then Zaratustra comes into the
picture and he says that we need to
revolt against Hinduism we need to
reform Hinduism he was another great
reformer we have so many reformers in
society in India today
We have so many so-called reformers of
Hindu society today who want to reform
the backward
religion called Hinduism. So Zaratusra
was one of those. He was born a Hindu.
He said I will reform Hinduism and I
will create this new religion or or an
inversion of Hinduism which eventually
came to be known as Zoroastrianism in
the English language. So this was a
polytheistic religion and now some
people will say it was a monotheistic
religion. Many parses will say it was
monotheistic. If Zoroastrianism was
monotheistic.
Why did why was Mitra a deity in
Zoroastrianism? Let me show you. Okay.
Okay.
First of all, the Romans worshiped
Mithra. Okay. So,
Mithraism.
What was Mithraism? An ancient Roman
mystery religion. Let's see what
Wikipedia has to say [clears throat]
about this. Even though it's not
necessarily a reliable source of
information. So it was a Roman mystery
religion. It was inspired by Iranian
worship of the Zoroastrian Zoroastrian
divinity mitra. The Zoroastrian god
in Iranian god.
Okay. So as you can see this is and
they'll say it's a yazata which is a
divinity which means a god. And who was
mitra?
It comes from the Sanskrit word mitum in
the common noun mitra vic common non
mitra. What is mitra? Mitra is a vic god
mitra varun.
So the point is
zorostinism was a polytheistic religion
but it was an inversion of Hinduism. The
das became the bad guys, the assuras
became the good guys that sort of thing.
And you see zoroastinism was not deeply
rooted in society. It was imposed
somehow upon society. We don't quite
know how.
And 1,00 years is not a long time for a
religion to take root. It has been
imposed externally on society. It did
not emerge organically like what we call
Hinduism did over thousands of years,
maybe tens of thousands of years.
Zorastrianism was an artificial
religion.
So it was imposed somehow on Persian
society. But when Islam came
I suppose Zurashism may have had this
sort of structure where if you take out
the priests the dust or whatever then
the whole society the whole system
collapses and that's why Zoroastrianism
was easy to wipe out from from Persia.
Of course some Zoroastrians refused to
convert and they had no option but to
flee they fled to India obviously
because well who else will welcome them
but their own people the Indians. So
that's why Zuroism was wiped out
rapidly. Hinduism could not be wiped
out. What about Gandhar and Kashmir? See
Gandhar present Afghanistan a thousand
years ago was almost entirely Buddhist
not Hindu.
If you want to differentiate between
Hinduism and Buddhism like today people
do. So then it was Buddhist not it was
not Hindu. There was Hinduism but it was
not not the majority thing. It was
Buddhism. You will see that central Asia
also was mostly Buddhist at that time.
And whenever you had Buddhism, there was
a very rapid conversion to Islam.
You've heard of Muhammad Guri, right?
Muhammad Guri's ancestors were Buddhists
who converted
to Islam. So wherever you had Buddhism,
for whatever reason, there was very
rapid conversion to Islam without much
resistance.
No fight back, just convert.
Why is it so? Well, ask yourselves about
the nature of Buddhism. I will not go
into that in detail. I will not. But
try and find out what is different
between Buddhism and Hinduism. Why did
all the Buddhist regions, regions of
Central Asia, Gandhar etc convert so
rapidly to Islam but Hinduism did not.
So Kashmir was Hindu. It was shite and
Kashmir did not convert to Islam for
several centuries after Gandhar.
It's only in the last 300 or so years
that were those mass conversions by
force, not voluntarily.
So these are the differences between
these different cultures and why
why the things happened the way they
did. All right.
Amisha says, why what did Islamic
scholars think of the pyramids in Egypt?
Were they considered some sort of pagan
monument? Were there any attempts to
Islamicize them in some way? The
pyramids, the pyramids. So,
so Egypt
loses its sovereignty first to the
Persians
about
about 2300
or so years ago. 2400 or so years ago,
give or take a century. Okay.
Then
Alexander walks in and liberates Egypt
from the Persians. But he rules he he he
installs a governor who reports to him.
So that's the beginning of the Greek
period of Egyptian history. So Egypt
still hasn't recovered its sovereignty.
It's now under Greek rule and Alexander
dies and then Egypt Egypt becomes ruled
by the tomic dynasty to
make dynasty. After the tomic dynasty
the last ruler was Cleopatra the great
famous after that you have the Roman
rule over Egypt and after that you have
the imposition of Christianity and all
that and eventually the Arabs take over.
So
what did the Arabs? So once the Arabs
take over the society is very rapidly
converted to Islam. Okay. Uh because of
a variety of reasons. Now so society the
society becomes Islamic
and then once a society becomes Islamic
you will say that there is a tendency to
destroy your own ances your own heritage
like the Taliban did with the Bian
Buddhas as an example. the old Taliban,
not the current Taliban who are friends
if you want to look at it that way.
Maybe you don't, whatever.
So, Egypt becomes an Islamic society.
And how did they regard the pyramids?
They regarded the pyramids as
manifestations of polytheism and
idolatry and paganism or whatever you
want to call it.
Bad stuff. Bad stuff. Bad stuff. So did
they ever try to islamicize Islamicize
these pyramids in some way? No. But the
some of them tried to destroy the
pyramids. So for example,
you had the great Islamic ruler Kuresh
ruler Salahadin Yubi Saladin
who fought the crusaders and uh who took
Jerusalem from the crusaders and then
retained Jerusalem and he fought against
Richard the Lionhe Heart. Long story. So
Salah Hudin was once the governor of
Egypt
and his second son Al Aziz Otman later
became the Sultan of Egypt. So Saladin's
son Al Aziz Usman he said that the
pyramids are evil. They are
manifestations of polytheist polytheism
and idolatry and they have to be
destroyed.
So he actually tried to destroy
several pyramids. He tried his best. He
had I don't know how many hundreds maybe
thousands of workers attempting to dis
dismantle pyramids. The pyramid of man
it still bears test testimony to what
happened. Let's let's Google that, shall
we? The pyramid of Manor.
Pyramid of Menow.
What's it look like?
Can you see this huge gigantic
slash in the pyramid? Uh let's go to the
Wikipedia page, shall we? One second.
I'm sure the Wikipedia page has a better
uh image of that vandalism.
So yeah,
as you can see, there's a big gash in
the pyramid. So that is what the the
Arabs what what uh this sultan aliz
utman that's this is what he was able to
do over a period of nearly one year he
had I don't know how many workers
working on this
and they wanted to dismantle the entire
pyramid and they were able to make very
slow progress uh I mean um you know one
or two stones stones per day they were
able to bring down once a stone will
fall into the sand. It'll sink into the
sand. It's almost impossible to remove.
So after a tremendous amount of effort,
they were able to make this gash into
this small pyramid smallalish pyramid
and then they gave up.
So they tried but maybe the pyramids
were built by aliens or whatever but
humans could not dis at least the the
Islamic rulers were not able to destroy
the pyramids. Eventually they gave up.
They said that you know what this is
beyond us. We'll just ignore these
things. But today Egypt in this is in
this very very paradoxical situation.
They don't like the pyramids. They
consider the pyramids even today to be a
manifestation of polytheism and whatever
else. All bad stuff according to them.
They hate the pyramids.
But the entire economy of Egypt is based
on the pyramids and they have to welcome
foreigners who want to see the pyramids.
That's the situation Egypt find itself
in. Paradoxical, isn't it?
Okay, multiple questions here. Salony
Mishra says, "How come Arab Muslims were
able to Arabicize the Egyptians but not
the Persians?" Math etc. says, "How did
generation of after generation of Turks
get irranicized, Persianized? Because
Ayati was the first person to rule Iran
in almost a millennium." Namisha says,
"Why didn't Iran start speaking Arabic
when it was under Muslim Arab rule much
longer than the 11th northern Africa or
Sicily?"
Right? Interesting questions. First of
all, one correctional
was not the first person to rule Iran in
almost a millennium. He was the third.
Who are the first two?
It was uh
Muhammad Raza Pahvi and his father. So
Muhammad Raz Phahabi Phahi's father was
what I forget his name. You can look it
up.
Razasha I think his name was Razasha. He
started ruling Porsche around 1925. Then
after him his son Muhammad Raza Palvi he
ruled Porsche until 1979 which which is
when the Islamic revolution happens in
Persia and Mr. Kmeni takes over. So Mr.
was a third person after those two shas
uh to rule Persia in almost a
millennium. What happened to Persia for
a millennium? You see around the what
11th century you had the Seljiguk Empire
that took over Persia. Okay. Uh there
were Turks who had converted to Islam.
They originally were Tangists or
polytheists obviously and they conquered
Persia and they established a huge
empire. The empire was culturally
Persian. So the so the Seljuks conquered
Persia in the 11th century and from that
time onwards Persia was ruled by Turks
and that's how all the transformations
happened in Persian society. Lots of
foreigners were settled in Persia. Today
about only about half of Persia's
population is Persian and even those
Persians are mixed with those foreigners
who are settled in Persia. Uh which is
why I say that you know the Persian
population of today is very different
from the Persian population of 500 AD
which was like us
genetically ethnically culturally and so
on.
Now the question is the Arabs were able
to Arabicize the Egyptians but not the
Persians. Why? Why didn't Iran start
speaking Arabic?
What happened? And how did Turks become
portionized is the question. See, the
Arabs were able to Arabize the Egyptians
because well, I would say for multiple
reasons. First of all, the Egyptian lang
language is very closely connected
related to the Arabic language.
They probably come under the semmitic
language familiar or something similar.
Let's quickly fact check what I just
said, shall we? Let's remove this. Okay.
Uh Egyptian language.
Egyptian language.
Um what language family does it belong
to? Language family. Language family.
Language family. Afroasiatic.
Afroasiatic. And subdivisions are
Berber, Chadic, Egyptian, Osmotic,
Sematic. Okay. So it's a sister language
of the sematic language family. And in
the sematic language family, you have
the Arabic language. Okay, I'll not I
don't have to prove that or should or do
I? Let's quickly take a look at that.
Okay. Uh where do I search? Okay, Arabic
language.
Arabic.
Yeah, Arabic is a central sematic
language. Okay, there there we have the
proof. Okay,
so where's the question? Where's the
question? Here we are.
So the Egyptian language was quite
similar to the Arabic language. That's
one reason why Arabic was very rapidly
successfully imposed on the people of
Egypt. And secondly, the conversion to
Islam also happened very rapidly. So
that's why Egypt was very rapidly
Arabized. I'm sure there must be other
factors and the other reasons but this
is what I can think of because the
languages were so similar. So the Arabs
imposed their language. Why not Bersia?
Because see this Zoroastrian religion
was easy to wipe out because it was an
artificial religion that was that had
not fully taken root in Persian society
in a in a deep way the way Hinduism had
taken root in Indian society for
thousands maybe tens of thousands of
years.
So that's why Zoroastan the Zoroastrian
religion was eradicated and replaced
with Islam very rapidly. But the Persian
language was very ancient going back 10
maybe thousands of years thousands of
years all the way back to Vic. They
would not give that up right because it
was so deep rooted and one of the
reasons the Persian language survived is
because of the shahaname written by
Ferdosi which became the standard for
Persian language for the Persian
language which is what the Persian
language spoken today is very similar to
the Persian language spoken during the
written in the Shaame.
The shaame if you look at the oldest
founding founding myths of the people of
Persia it essentially echoed rigidic
stories we'll not go into that in this
question
so that's why the religion was replaced
by Islam but the language could not be
eradicated but but what happened is that
the script the Arabic script was imposed
on Persia the Persians had their own
uniform script that was dismantled
discarded and the Arabic script was
imposed in Persia and the Persians
modified the Arabic script somewhat.
Okay.
And there are certain certain
pronunciations that don't exist in the
Arabic language but they exist in
Persian language in the Persian language
like Jer. The Arabs can't say the
Persians have this the the the
pronunciation.
So they have modified the Arabic script.
the jer term has three dots instead of
instead of whatever exists in Arabic. So
it's they they have kind of repurposed
the Arabic script somewhat to use it for
the Persian language. But some of the
Arabic things have crept crept into the
Persian language. For example, instead
of saying parsley, they say farsy,
right? Because the Arabs can't say P.
They can only say f or b. So the
Persians had the choice of either saying
bars or farsy. So they chose far. It
should have been parsi from Persia Pua.
So some changes happened but overall the
Persian language survived because it was
so ancient the Arabs could not approve
it. The Persians would not give it up.
Uh so that explains hopefully um why
Iran did not start speaking Arabic. Iran
Arabic never took over in Iran became
mainstream in Iran.
uh but obviously the Quran etc in Arabic
and the Persian did not use Persian as
far as I know in a large scale way uh
for the for the Quran it was always
Arabic. Now why did Turks become irrani
persianized? What happened? See Persia
was a very ancient civilization as we
know right
and and and because they had converted
to Islam
so there was no need to destroy their
their their language and culture and
whatnot as far as the non-religious
aspects are concern are concerned so if
you so so Persia was was was you could
say
what's the term it was it was what is
the term
So Persia was was this great culture,
prestigious culture, prestigious Persia
was Persian culture was prestigious.
So the Arabs so the Arabs did not want
to become Persianized because they said
that we are the originators of Islam. We
should not adopt any foreign culture.
But the Turks were happy to do that. The
Turks wherever they went, they adopted
the local cultures in India. They they
became the Turk Shahis. They adopted
Hinduism and Buddhism in India
and when they when they conquered Persia
they became Persianized because they
wanted to adopt the absorb the more
prestigious culture Turks married
Iranian women
lots of them and that's why if you see
the paintings of Turkey of of Persian
rulers from like Nadia or whoever you
will see them having slanted eyes like
the like the Turk peoples of Central
Asia.
So uh the Turks absorbed Persian culture
because Persian culture was way more
prestigious than any other culture they
knew. That's how it went.
Tuhinre says Tuhinre says the west has
organized universities like Oxford,
Harvard, Yale from medieval ages. Well,
Yale isn't medieval. Yale is more
recent. But okay, we Indians were also
wealthy and knowledgeable to their
levels. To their levels.
Okay. Yet why did we not have such
organized institutions for education?
Okay.
See this is the problem with the Indian
education system. I don't blame my dear
friend Tuhin for asking this question.
Probably they never thought the truth
when when he studied right. It's not his
fault.
We were not knowledgeable to the levels
of the west. We were the originators of
all knowledge.
The west absorbed and digested our
knowledge and now the present at it as
their knowledge. Have you heard of
Takshashila?
The university of Takshashila?
That's the oldest university we know of
in in the world. There must be older
ones too. But I can think of Takashila
which was founded maybe around sometime
in the first millennium BC.
Vishnu Gupta Chanaka was a student in
Takuashila and later he was a professor
in Takashila.
Have you heard of Vikramashila? Have you
heard of Odantauri? Have you heard of
Nalanda?
Have you heard of Shardit?
Have you heard of Walabi in western
India?
There are so many universities that that
I can name and there must be way more
that whose names have been erased.
We invented the concept of the
university.
When the University of Nalanda was
destroyed by the Turks about a thousand
years ago roughly, it is said that the
library burned for several months.
That's how much
that was the the the volume of of of
books, texts, whatever you want to call
it in the library.
We had we were the inventors of the
concept of the university. So I'm not
sure why some Indians are not aware of
this. I don't blame the Indians who are
not who are unaware of this. I blame
their teachers. I blame the rotten
education system of India.
Right?
Udit Mahesh says, "How did England
become the origin of the
English-speaking people which it is
today? Did the Anglo-Saxons wipe out the
Kelts from England before achieving
complete settlement over that region
like the US did in North America? Or did
the Anglo-Saxons raid the Celtic people
and settle and intermingle with the
local population and the region became
England as it's known today?" The name
England
comes from the angles. Now let's let's
start at the beginning. Let's start at
the very beginning like I always like to
do. You've heard of something called
Stonehenge, right? Stonehenge. Let's
Google that. Stonehenge.
[snorts]
Stonehenge is a prehistoric landmark.
It's How old is it? Let me see quickly.
How old is Stonehenge?
It was built what uh about 2600 BC or
maybe 3,000 BC or something roughly. So
it's about 5,000 years old. Stonehenge.
This is in England. So the original
English people built this monument
Stonehenge. I'll not go into the details
of what this is.
So the original people of the islands
built it started building it about three
about 5,000 years ago. Those people
their male lineages have disappeared
because there was an invasion of these
British of the British islands by a
group of fantastic people who are now
today called the Yamnaya.
Okay. Um they had the Haplau group R1B.
They were absolute
what can I say barbarians let's say and
they invaded and conquered the islands
and killed off all the males and then
proceeded to have offspring with the
females who were subjugated.
That was the origin of the Celtic
people.
Typically Celtic people have red hair.
Okay. uh and and the Celtic people they
live they lived in the British islands
Scotland, Ireland, Britain, etc. They
also lived in Spain and in western
France and all over France, Gaul also
presented Switzerland. So that's the
original homeland of the Celtic peoples.
Um
then what happens is that the Romans
conquer the region and they take over
what you know large parts of what is
today the UK. Uh up to the they did not
conquer the northern parts. They built a
wall there to keep the barbarians away.
The barbarians had red hair and blonde
hair. And for a few centuries Rome ruled
what is today the UK or some parts of
it. Some not not all of it. not Ireland,
not Scotland, but the rest of it. Then
the Romans eventually had to leave
because their empire crumbled. And then
you have an invasion of the British
islands from Germany. A bunch of Germans
invade
uh the what is today the UK. It's the
Angles, which is one ethnic group, and
the Saxons who came from present day
Saxony. The Angles and the Saxons, both
Germanic tribes, come and they attempt
to invade the islands or multiple
decades. Eventually, they take over the
islands. They subjugate the local Celtic
people, the red-headed people,
and they establish the Anglo-Saxon rule
over
um
the British islands, not all of them,
but what is present day England, more or
less. Okay. So, you have the
Anglo-Saxons who are ruling now. So, now
we have how many ethnic groups in
England in in the UK? You have the the
Kelts who are the descendants of the
original women and the Yamna invader
males
and then you also have the Anglo-Saxons.
So two ethnic groups.
Then in the year 1066 AD there was a new
invasion the last successful invasion of
England which was carried out by Normans
who were of Nordic ancestry mixed with
the French.
The Normans and they invade England. uh
their leader the ruler was William
Duke of Normandy who came to be known as
William the Conqueror and now you have a
period of time where the Normans who are
French-speaking Nordic people who rule
England
and it is the combination of these three
ethnic groups the Kelts
the Anglo-Saxons and the Normans it is
the combination of these three ethnic
groups their cultures and their
languages that gave rise to what is
today English so English is a Germanic
language. It's not a Celtic language.
What are the Celtic languages? Well, um
Irish, GI, Scottish, these are Scottish
most likely. Yeah, these are Celtic
languages. English is a Germanic
language. It's it's an invasive language
actually and that's how it happened in
very brief. That's how it went. So there
are three ethnic groups that
intermingled and uh today which is the
dominant culture and language English.
Tuhin Ray says the first sorry Tuhin Ray
says the South American civilizations
like the Aztecs or the Incas outnumbered
the Spanish very heavily. How did these
flourishing civilizations fall to the
Spanish conquest like a stack of cards
like a pack of cards? What happened is
the question.
So in north in in central America,
present day Mexico, you had the Aztec
Empire, the Triple Alliance,
which was the dominant uh dominant
force, you know, geopolitical force in
the region in present day Mexico, that
region. And in south on the west coast
of South America you had the Inca
Empire.
Totally different empires. Let's let's
take a look at the map so that we
understand what I am talking about. One
second. Okay. All right. Let's go to the
map of the world and we'll check out
what regions I am referring to.
So we go to the Americas. When we talk
about the Inca Empire, it was located in
this region around Mexico City. Mexico
City was called Tenokitlan.
All right? Mexico City was called
Tenokitlan. And that was the capital of
the triple alliance, the Aztec Empire.
And then you had the Inca Empire which
was based in Peru, right? Where is the
great lake? Is this the great lake? This
is the lake Titikaka which is well the
Inca Empire kind of emerged on the banks
of this lake and it became a very
massive empire and it it was the largest
empire of its type in the world the Inca
Empire. It was established by the great
king Pakoti.
So now what happened? So you have these
great civilizations and empires, not
merely empire but also civilization,
right? Ancient cultures and they were
very populous the Aztecs as well as the
Incas. So what happened? How did the
bunch of ragtag spaniads barbarians take
over? So the Aztec Empire fell to
Hernand Cortez
in the year 1520 21 or something and the
Inca Empire fell to another barbarian
called Franchesco Pedarro in the 1530s
1530s all the way to 1570s it's a long
process but you can say 1530s that's
when the Inca Empire felt fell
so it all the whole process begins with
this misguided person called Christopher
Columbus who was looking for India who
stumbled into the Americas and he he
claimed he has discovered India. Then
the Spanish very rapidly understood that
it is not India that he has discovered.
It is a new land and they proceeded to
brutally colonize it.
Um the French also tried and that's a
long story. Okay. The French attempted
to do that. They were massacred by the
by the Spaniards. Matamaza no m okay
whatever the place is called.
But uh you had you had multiple
expeditions by the Spanish to more and
more colonize the Americas. And the
Spanish brought with them not just
brutality, not just the the their their
foreign religion, Christianity, but they
brought with them the diseases of
Eurasia.
The worst of these was smallpox. So when
Hernand Cortez was in the process of
invading the Aztec Empire, he came with
a small number of men. How did he
conquer an empire that had hundreds of
thousands of soldiers?
One factor was smallox. There was a
horrific smallox epidemic that was
raging across the Aztec Empire. The
people of the new so-called new world of
the Americas, they had zero immunity to
the Euro Eurasian diseases. So they were
just dying off
dying left right center right tremendous
uh death toll tremendous mortality rate.
So you have them trying to survive the
small pox. Many of them are dying and
then the Azak Empire was a hegemonic
empire and you had many other states
that they had absorbed through force
through hedgemony and those people they
obviously wanted to be free of the
Aztec. So they said oh a bunch of
foreigners have come let's align with
them temporarily the foreigners will go
back right well it turns out the
foreigners never went back. So the the
guys of Pizaro, they had about 20 30,000
allies with them who were willing to
fight on their side and that's why there
was a massive massive battle and smallox
turned out to be the the the you know
game changer the deciding factor and
that's how the Azak Empire was
dismantled by Karan Cortez not with 200
men but with tens of thousands of of of
native indigenous allies who then also
were eventually brutally barbar
barbarous ly killed and converted.
Killed and or converted by the
Spaniards.
That's one reason. Okay, that's about
the Aztec Empire. What about the uh Inca
Empire? So, you see after the conquest
of the Aztec Empire, you had these
expeditions that were going out in the
into the Americas. You had the Narvay
expedition whose great survivor was
Kabisadwaka.
uh that was that that tried to go into
what is today Florida to explore the
land and they brought with them smallpox
and other diseases. Then you had the
Coronado expedition which happened later
actually in the 1540s or something and
then you had the Herand the Sto
expedition who brought with him pigs. So
all these expeditions and all these
paners they brought in small pox and it
this small pox eventually came breached
all the way down into South America.
And when Franchesco Pizaro was in his in
the process of trying to invade and
conquer the Inca Empire, it was beset by
smallpox. Uh the last great Inca emperor
was Atawalpa.
Okay. And his father died to died of
smallpox. And then Atawalpa had a
conflict with his brother who eventually
who initially became the emperor. And
then Atawalpa became the emperor. He was
treacherously captured and eventually
killed by Pizaro and that's how the Inca
Empire also went down.
So you have small pox playing a big
role. You have uh indigenous traitors
you could say who allied with the
Spaniards who also played a big role.
The same thing happened in the Inca
Empire as well. And these are the
reasons why the Spaniards were able to
conquer
u the Aztecs and the Incas in brief. If
you want to understand in more detail,
check out my podcasts on the
understanding America series which is
currently on hiatus.
Right.
Amisha says, "How accurate is the idea
this that Spanish colonization in the
Americas was significantly more brutal
than the other colonial powers which is
the French and the English."
The Spanish were pretty brutal, very
brutal. They wiped out the entire
population of Hispanola which is the
island which is today Cuba and uh
Dominica for let's let's where is
Hispanola
not Dominica not Cuba and Dominica but
Heii and the Dominican Republic. This
island here was called Hispanola. It was
the home of the Ara people and
Christopher Columbus uh was the governor
for a while of this island and he
exterminated those people, wiped them
out of existence, genocided them.
Um
so that's one. So there is Spanish
brutality, right?
Um and the Spanish also brutalized the
Mexicans which is the Aztec triple
alliance, the Incas. They conducted all
kinds of bar barbaric genocides,
massacres. Uh when you had uh the
Coronado expedition which started in
Mexico which was then called New Spain,
it went further north into Arizona etc.
Uh what they did is that they had this
directive from their from their king
from their government. Then you say your
job is to find a treasure and wealth for
the king but it's also to convert the
local people to Christianity
and you are allowed to fight the local
people but you have to first give them a
chance to convert.
So they they had this legal document
which they had to read out saying that
you know this land is now taken over by
this by the king of Spain and this
document shows you that it is it is
legal and you are exhorted to convert to
Christianity if you do that then we will
not murder you and and rape you and
enslave you but we will treat you as
secondass citizens and we'll allow you
to live as long as you become Christian
and if you don't then we are at liberty
to kill you all. And the Spaniards would
you know what they would do? They would
stand outside a native city at like in
the middle of the night
5 kilometers away and they will read it
out to nobody in particular but in the
direction of the city and then they'll
say yeah you see they did not convert
they did not listen to us they didn't
convert so let's go and kill them all so
they were pretty brutal in that manner
so the Spanish were very brutal but once
the natives converted to Christianity
they were allowed to live they were not
massacred there was obviously and they
were not enslaved also So if they
converted to Christianity, they merely
became servants and secondass citizens,
those who survived the small pox. That's
the deal with the Spanish colonization.
Pretty brutal. They destroyed the native
culture, language, religion as far as
possible. In certain parts of South
America, you still have local languages
that survive. Some local culture
survives. Sometimes some local religions
also survive. But mostly it's all all
the official languages. I mean the
official language in all the countries
in South America is Spanish. Apart from
Brazil which is Portuguese, a different
story. When it comes to the other
colonial powers, French, the French and
the British, the French,
they tried to be nice to the natives,
they actually tried to be friends with
the natives as as long as was possible.
Initially, initially,
I'm talking about the 1500s. Later when
the French established colonies in North
America,
north way more north of Florida in what
is now Canada, etc., Quebec and so on,
they were pretty brutal against the
natives. Okay,
but the the French did not win the war,
right? The the war to colonize the North
America. It is the English who won that.
Now, were the English less brutal than
the Spanish?
The English were far more brutal.
They wiped out the the Native Americans.
They killed millions of bisons. They
almost completely exterminated the bison
from North America because the Native
Americans depended on the bison for
their for their for living.
And today, how many Native Americans
exist in North America? And what is
their status in society today?
I would say overall if you look at the
colonization of the Americas about a 100
million native Americans were
exterminated
most of that happened at the hands of
the Anglo
not so much the Spanish. So overall the
Anglo were the most brutal very
systematic
very bureaucratic about that. They
passed laws.
They passed laws
that said that you know various large
parts of North America would be cleared
of natives. The natives would be moved
to other parts of North America. You had
the trail of tears. You had the uh
so-called Indian wars that went on for
like a couple of centuries in which they
were essentially genocided out of out of
existence almost out of out of
existence. And today the Native
Americans are allowed to live on small
parcels of land called reservations
where they technically have sovereignty
of some kind apparently to some extent
not real sovereignty but you know local
police level sovereignty they have and
it's typically baron land and there's
not not much you can do to you know
generate an income or whatever. So
overall the Spanish were indeed brutal.
They were indeed barbaric but not as
much as the Anglo.
Okay.
Math N C F L M okay whatever says were
the Turk Shahis Sanskritized Turks or
did they follow Tangorism?
The original religion of the Turk people
and the Hunic people is Tangorism.
It's called Tangism in English. And
there is this myth myth or misconception
which is very prevalent today that
Tangorism is a monotheistic religion.
They worship one god called Tangri
which is utter nonsense. Tangriism is a
polytheistic religion. They worship the
skyfather Tangri and the earth mother
Umay. They also worship their ancestors.
They worship forest spirits. They
worship so many other divinities. It's a
polytheistic religion. But today there
is this effort to to portray theism as a
monotheistic religion which is a lie, a
malicious lie.
So theism is a polytheistic religion.
Now the Turks and the Huns wherever they
traveled they absorbed the local
religion and culture wherever they went.
So so the Turk Shahis were most likely
descendants of the Shwa Hunas
and maybe some other Turk elements were
there and they ruled
various parts of Gandhara essentially
that region for a while. How long did
they rule? Maybe a couple of centuries
or so and they fought the Arabs. They
defended India from the Arabs. Okay.
Uh, so how long did the torch his
How long did they rule?
How long did
did they rule?
Brah, did they rule?
Okay, a couple of centuries, roughly
couple of centuries, right? Um,
Zabulistan, Kabul Gandhar, etc. So what
was their religion? Were they
Sanskritized? What is the meaning of
Sanskritization? I'm not quite sure.
They practiced Hinduism and Buddhism. It
is alleged that they practiced more
Buddhism than than Hinduism, whatever.
But they practiced both religions. They
patronized both religions. And as long
as they ruled, they defended India from
the Arabs.
Um and eventually they were defeated by
the Arabs. They were one of their kings
was forced to convert to Islam and one
of his ministers, one of this king's
ministers who was a Brahman,
he fought the Arabs, he decided to fight
the Arabs and he set up the Hindu Shahi
dynasty.
So after the Turk Shahis you have the
rule of the Hindu Shahis and then things
happened as we know. So there was a deal
they were not Sanskritized, they were
Indianized. I don't know what
Sanskritized means.
Did they speak Sanskrit? They probably
spoke the Gandhari language or maybe a
Turk language. I'm not quite sure. But
they adopted Indian titles etc. And
their inscriptions etc are probably in
Sanskrit. But they were not
Sanskritized. They were Indianized. If
you adopt Sanskrit and Hinduism,
Buddhism, it means you are Indianized,
not Sanskritized, not Brahmanized or
Brahminical religion or whatever. Okay.
So that's the deal with the Turkah.
Himmanu Sharma says, "We know Chungis
Khan was one of history's most
influential rulers. Yet his burial site
remains undiscovered. Where is his grave
believed to be located?" Let me tell you
where his grave is believed to be
located.
Okay. Uh Buran Khaldun Khani.
Check this out. Khani Khan Khi strictly
protected zone area. Okay, so that is
the thing. Uh we can take a look at the
map. Okay, I I don't need to go to the
map for that. And there is this great
mountain there in the Khani.
Maybe we can take a look at that on the
map. Why not? Yeah. So we go to the map.
We search for Khani
strictly protected area where nobody is
allowed.
Okay, Khan Kenti zoom. There we go. So,
we zoom we use the satellite image. So,
this is the Khan Kenti region, strictly
protected zone. Huge huge uh region part
of Mongolia,
north of Alanbatar,
south of uh the Russian part of
Mongolia. And if you look at Burkhan
Kaldun,
well, this is the mountain that uh
Chingis Khan you know he lived in this
region and uh as a child
and it is believed that his grave his
resting place is somewhere in this
region and like I said the Khan Kenti uh
region is is a strictly protected region
u no one's allowed there during the
Soviet era when Mongolia was a Soviet
vasal
that region was a no-go zone and even
today you know access to the region is
is strict strictly controlled and there
have been European expeditions to to the
region who have sought to discover the
resting place of Chingish Khan but
nobody has succeeded this far. So it is
believed
before I elaborate further let me just
put this on the record. It is believed
that Chingis Khan's
grave burial place is in the Khan Khanti
region the Burhan Kaldun region
somewhere around that place. Now how do
we know that this is the case? See when
Shere Marco Polo the Italian traveler
traveled to Mongolia, he was told this
nice story that when Chingis Khan died,
they brought his body back to the to you
know his childhood, the place where he
lived his childhood which is the the
Burhan Kaldun mountain region and he was
buried there and after he was buried the
place was trampled over by a million
horses apparently and a river was
diverted over the place. So the river
flows over the burial place now and
whoever the soldiers who buried in him
they were killed and any traveler who
came on okay who saw what happened was
also killed
that's the story that was told to Marco
Polo and this story traveled into Europe
so the Europeans have been fascinated
and the westerners have been fascinated
about finding the burial place because
apparently if you find his burial place
then it will have a tremendous amount of
wealth and gold and treasure and
whatnot. So they crave to discover the
resting place of Chingishan. Now what do
I make of this? Me personally
what I have to say about this is that
Chinghan's burial place will never be
discovered. Never ever ever ever be
discovered.
It won't. Why do I say this?
Because first of all if you understand
Chingghis Khan and I have studied
Chinghan in great detail for decades.
If you understand Chingghistan you will
understand that he did not care about
wealth first of all. So if he would be
buried somewhere he would not be buried
with tremendous amount of wealth or
whatever.
Secondly when Chigasan's father died
what kind of burial was Yugi given? He
was given what they call a sky burial.
Sky burial. I will not Google it and
show you the images because not
appropriate. What you do in a sky burial
is that you the person who is who is
dead, who has died, you do whatever
prayers etc you want to do. You strip
the body of all its clothes. You take it
to a hill and you leave it there
and the birds will take care of the
rest. That's called a sky burial. Very
similar to what the Zoroastrians have.
The Zoroastrians also have something
very similar to this. In Tibet today,
they still practice sky burials. Tibet
both
and I suppose in Mongolia also today
they some people may practice sky
burials. So when Chingish Khan's father
died, he was given well he was kind of
his body was abandoned
but u yeah they practiced sky burials
and it is my opinion that chases Khan
would have preferred to be buried or or
you know for his funeral arrangements to
followed that procedure. Why?
because he died.
He died in what is today China. He was
fighting the Chinese and somehow he
died. We don't we're not quite sure how
he died. But his last order before dying
was to his brothers, go and destroy the
kingdom of Shishia. Destroy them. And
that's what happened. His order was
carried out even after he died. So he
was on this campaign in China to to
reconquer China because the Chinese had
rebelled against him once again. When he
went for this uh for the conquest of the
Quaras Empire to teach them a lesson,
the Chinese rebelled who he had
initially conquered. So he went back to
China to conquer to to crush the
rebellion and somehow for whatever
reason he died there. That was a huge
distance away from Burhan Kaldun the
Kenti Khan Kenti mount. region. So in in
those days, how do you transport a body
over a thousand plus kilometers without
it decomposing? It's not you don't want
that to happen. It's not dignified,
right? So most likely he would have been
given a sky burial wherever he died.
That's what I believe. I have no proof,
but I have a reasonably deep
understanding of Shri Chingis Khan and
what kind of person he was. So I don't
believe he was buried anywhere in the
Khan Khandi region. He would have been
given a sky burial and his spirit would
have flown
and reconnected with his ancestors. That
was the Mongolic belief system. But then
why was Marco Polo told the story?
Because he was a barbarian from a far
away foreign country. And you don't tell
the truth to barbarians.
You mislead them.
So I believe that Changistan's burial
place will never be found and that's how
it should be.
No club says I'm following you for 2
years discovered you for the from
Ranir's podcast.
Well thank you very much sir. Thank you.
Could you please explain the great man
theory in detail and what are their
traits? So the great man theory is an
ancient well not ancient it's a it's a
theory that's been around for the past
couple of hundred years and it says that
all major geopolitical events that drive
history forward
who is responsible for that it's
typically a few great men.
Okay,
let me give you some examples. Alexander
the Great,
great man, right?
Then you have Julius Caesar, another
great man.
Uh you have Napoleon, great man. You
have Chingish Khan, a great man. If you
go back all the way back in Indian
history, we have King Sudas, a great
man. Before that or after that after
kings that great man who fought the
battle and won the battle of the 10
kings 10 plus kings then you have Shri
Ram great man we worship him as an
incarnation of Shir Vishnu today then
you have Shri Krishna another great man
if you look at more recent Indian
history Vishnu Gupta Chanaka Chandra
Gupta Moria Ashok Kaneshka these are the
people who drove Indian history who who
sh and who shaped the course of Indian
history. You have a great man who
emerged out of the out of Arabia,
Prophet Muhammad who changed the course
of world history, didn't he? No question
about that. In more recent times, we
have Napoleon Bonapart who changed the
course of European history. We have the
iron chancellor Ottoon Bismar. We have
the great evil man Adolf Hitler with
Stalin. We have Maadun.
We have in Turkey Mustafa Kimalaturk who
changed the course of world history. We
have the Turkish Sultan Salem II who
took Constantinople and changed world
history. So my point is the the theory
the great man theory says that it is a
few great men in world history who who
who
shaped the course of world history.
It is their leadership and their great
traits or whatever that is the uh the
the factor the the force that shapes the
course that the world takes. That is the
great man theory. Um what do I think of
this? Well, you know today there's a lot
of criticism that this theory takes
because it says great man not great
person. It doesn't include women.
So that's one criticism that has emerged
in the 20th and 20th more 21st century
that it is a misogynistic theory. Women
aren't included.
Okay, that's one thing. And apart from
that, it says that apparently the great
man theory says that you know leadership
traits are are people are born with
those leadership traits and leadership
isn't learned. It is it is innate in you
or that sort of thing. I don't agree
with that at all in case it is true
because if you look at various leaders
like uh whether it is king sodas,
whether it is Julius Caesar, whether it
is Sri Ram Shri Krishna, whether it is
um
Chandra Gupta Moria,
whether it is Changis Khan, whether it
is Napoleon, they all were not they may
have had some leadership traits in them
when they were born, but it was the
events of their early that shaped them
and and forged the leader in fire of in
the fire of trials and tribulations. So,
so leaders, you know, some people may
have leadership qualities. They may be
born leaders, but they they would never
potentially never go through that those
those tribulations and trials that
forges a true leader. Then maybe lots of
leaders simply did not emerge because of
that. So the point is there are some
criticisms that are levied at the great
man theory but in my opinion it makes a
lot of sense.
The course of world history has always
all major world events all major
geopolitical changes in world history
have occurred because of warfare and
what drives warfare is typically what
they call great men. I can't think of
too many great women. Maybe the world is
an evil place. Maybe the world is an
evil patriarchal place. It is what it is
right I am who am I to judge that we
don't judge we simply observe we simply
observe and we notice the patterns and
then we discuss the patterns so if you
look at the patterns it's clear that
it's been these great men who have
shaped the history of the world and that
essentially is the great man theory you
may agree or disagree with it you may
consider it to be you may consider it to
be a misogynistic theory whatever
outdated theory that's entirely up to
you but that's what great man theory
>> [snorts]
>> Okay, let's talk about the Chinese and
plagiarism. Ashish Karn Karnashish says
Chinese are plagiarizing Indian dresses
and cultural items and calling them
Persian or from western regions of China
because they can't digest India
influence them heavily. How should we
Indians deal with this? Same thing with
Hindu numerals. I don't know why they
add Arabic the term Arabic to it because
it was invented in India really now says
Chinese use modified Indian clothing
jewelry and classical dances in so many
of their productions but fiercely deny
any Indian origin for them saying it's
central Asian or Turk or Persian
influence that even India got this
culture from there they deny Gandhar was
literally India and say Pompei Lakshmi
is not Indian
So what are we talking about here?
Let me show you. Uh let me show you.
Okay, give me a second. So here is one
example.
This is from Twitter or X. Let me first
remove this. Uh we have it. So this is
the Shin of which means the Chinese
embassy in France. They say that this is
a costume from Zing Jang. Please take a
look at the costume. Does this look like
a costume from China?
This is so clearly so clearly an Indian
costume. The Chinese are claiming
claiming it's from Shinjang.
Now, let's take a look at something
else.
This is a new controversy that has
emerged in Twitter, which is good. Uh
they are calling this a traditional
Chinese clothing from western regions of
China. Once again, it's Indian clothing.
And I'll not play the video because of
whatever copyright thing. But you see
even the dance is Indian, right? It's
inspired from India and whatever this
other thing is.
The Chinese are essentially plagiarizing
Indian culture [clears throat]
and that's what we are discussing here.
Right?
So what they claim is that it's either
Persian or Central Asian or Turk. Well,
if you just look at the historical
record of the kind of dresses Indian
ladies used to wear during let's say uh
the Gupta period, the Kushan period, the
modern period, it's clear that these
dresses are of Indian origin. But the
Chinese want to claim these and they
claim it's it's from wherever Persia
Persian clothing is Islamic clothing in
the past 1500 or so years 14 12300 years
and before that the ch the Persians did
not wear the kind of clothes Indians
wear in Persian ladies
so it can't be Persian
Central Asia the climate is such that
you can't wear such clothing in central
to Asia. The Turks for the past at least
thousand years they've been Islamiz
Islamicized. They don't wear such
clothing. The Arabs they don't wear such
clothing. They wear burkas.
So it's clearly Indian clothing the
Chinese are trying to pass off as either
Turic or Central Asian or Persian or
Arabic but not Indian.
Right? If you watch the movie Aladin,
there's a movie called Aladin, a Disney
movie. There's this character called
Jasmine in that. Okay,
let's take a look at that. Uh, Daisy
Alladin
1992 film. Okay, let's take a look at
the images. So, this is the main
character Aladin and there is this girl
called Jasmine.
Jasmine costume. Let's take a look at
the costume.
So, this Oh, come on, man. Where's the
original?
Okay, just look at this. So, this is the
kind of dress that Jasmine wears. Once
again, it is it is being passed off as
as an Arabic costume, but Arabic ladies
would never wear such a thing. It's
unimaginable. Once again, this comes
from India. It's inspired by India, but
it's passed off as Arabic. So, even
Hollywood does this. As you can see,
this is not an Arabic style of dressing.
This may be
but this is not.
So the west does it, the Chinese do it,
everybody does it and they get away with
it. Why is that? Why does everybody get
away with this? Because
because we don't take ownership of our
culture.
Take the example of yoga. Yoga has been
plagiarized and distorted the world
over. the the Europeans, the the
Americans, the West has they have taken
over yoga and they have distorted it
beyond belief. Hot yoga, cold yoga, dog
yoga, goat yoga, drunk yoga. I don't
even know what other what other forms of
yoga. It's because we have never
bothered to take ownership of yoga. I
have been saying this for years. India
should India needs the government of
India needs to wake the hell up and
establish a yoga a a global yoga
standards institute
a global institute of yoga which will
which will decide what is yoga and what
is not yoga. It will decide the
standards of yoga. It will play the role
that the that the Shaolin temple plays
for kung fu.
The Shaolin temple decides what is kung
fu and what is not. Not any goddamn
thing can be called kung fu, right?
Similarly, we need to have this in India
but we are not doing it. The government
of India is simply not interested. India
has become a secular nation which
rejects its cultural
heritage.
Oh, we have established a world you got.
Nice, fantastic, great thing.
Beyond that, what that's so easy.
Do a little bit of hard work sometimes,
right? And similarly, we need to be very
clear about what constitutes Indian
culture and what
what for example the dresses are these
Indian dresses or Chinese dresses. So,
we need to reclaim our culture. We need
to take ownership of of our culture. We
people can keep on doing it but it can
be denied. The moment the government
declares something to be Indian
heritage. It's very hard for others to
to fight back against that once we do it
officially. But the government of India
is simply not concerned. I have no idea
what they're doing and it's incredibly
frustrating. It is what it is. There we
have it.
Okay. A question from a year ago. Was he
a hidden Jew? And we're talking about
Mustafa.
So somebody someone else says it's not
clear what he was. He was definitely not
a Muslim. He was a Freemason. However,
his followers created a cult around him
studying verses from the Quran and
replacing Allah and the prophets with
Ataturk.
Okay. So the question actually is
who was Mustafa Kimal Ataturk? The
dictator of Turkey who saved Turkey from
the west.
Was he a hidden Jew? Was he a Freemason?
Was he something else? Was he not a
Muslim? What was he? Was he not Turkish?
What was the deal with Mustafa?
What we know for sure is that he tried
to eradicate Islam from Turkey.
He his name was Mustafa. Kimal Kamal
comes later. Kimal is an Arabic word
which means perfection or perfect. Uh
his name was merely Mustafa. He did not
have a surname. His father's name was
Ali Raza. His mother's name was Zubeda.
His sister's name was Makbula. How do I
know all this? I've studied Ataturk in
detail.
So the the his name is today called
Mustafa Kimal Ataturk. The word Kamal
was added by one of his teachers,
mathematics teachers who found that he
was brilliant in mathematics. And
Ataturk was a title given to him by the
people of Turkey after he saved Turkey
from the from the west. Ataturk means
the father of the Turks.
Now what what's the deal?
Was he not Muslim? So look,
first of all, if you look at Ataturk,
let's take a look at let's let's uh
Google.
Let's Google him. Ataturk.
So if you look at Ataturk when he was
young,
this is a younger Ataturk. You can see
that he has blue eyes.
And uh if you
atatur
apparently
Oh, I had no idea I could smile. So if
you see him as a young man,
you will see he looks kind of European.
Even in in his older age, he look
European. Uh but if you see the color
pictures of Ataturk, you will see that
he has blue eyes.
And uh why am I searching for young
images? Because typically hair color
changes as you grow older. When he was
young, he had blonde hair. And you can
look it up yourself. I'm not going to
waste your time looking for the specific
images. When he was young, he had blonde
hair and blue eyes. Why does a Turk have
that? See, Turks,
they they have Greek and Anatolian
ancestry. The Greeks were not
necessarily blue-eyed and and blonde
people. The Greeks typically have dark
eyes and hair. So why did Ataturk have
blue eyes and blonde hair? His mom, his
mother, Zubeda,
most likely was Albanian.
Okay, Albania is further west in Europe,
slightly east of Italy across the
Adriatic. So his mother was Albanian and
from her he probably got and and she had
blue eyes and blonde hair. So that's how
he got those characteristics. Now his
father was a Turk, clear-cut Turk and
they were all Muslims. Father, mother
both both Muslims as far as is known.
When he was young, he was involved in
various organizations. something called
union in progress.
Something called uh there was something
called union union in progress. I am not
sure if he was ever a freemason. There
are some allegations that are
unsupported by known evidence as far as
I know that he became a freemason. What
I can tell you is that he tried to ban
Freemasonry in Turkey in the year what
1930 something. Let's let's Google that
as well, shall we?
Did Ataturk
did At
ban Freemasonry?
Okay. While not a direct ban, his
government oversaw the closure of
Freemason lodges in Turkey in 1935 based
on the rationale that their principles
were incompatible with the nationalistic
policy
and in response to external. Okay. So
Ataturk did not do a direct ban but he
did close uh Freemason lodges in Turkey
in 1935.
So if he was a Freemason, why would he
do that?
Right? So the Freemasonry angle doesn't
seem to be correct. What about the
Jewish angle? Some people accuse him of
being Jewish. Well, I can tell you his
father was Turkish to the best of my
knowledge. You can check it out. And his
mother was Albanian but Muslim. So I
don't see a Jewish angle there either.
If you see for a person to be Jewish
their mother has to be Jewish but I
personally have not seen any Jewish
angle to his mom to his mother Zubeda.
So you know there are all these um
theories that float around on the
internet that was a freebason he was a
Jew or whatever um but I've seen none of
that. Uh I've seen evidence I' I've not
seen any evidence for that. Was he not a
Muslim? There could be some truth to
that. U he tried his best to to
eradicate Islam from his nation. So you
would not do that if you were Muslim,
right? So that probably there is truth
to that. Beyond that, I can't see
anything else.
Aayush Singh says, "Why call a nation
sorry, why call a region northeast when
it is the far east of India?" This shows
the leadership of the nation has no
ambition of getting over this colonial
mentality. Let's take a look at the map
of India.
What are we talking about? We're talking
about what they call northeast India.
Northeast India is these states over
here, right? Arunachal Pradesh, Assam,
Megal, Nagal, Manipur, uh, Tripura,
Misaram.
These are the states that constitute
what we call the northeast. If you look
at the geography of India, the north is
Ladak, Kashmir etc. South is uh
Kerala, Tamil Nadu, Lanka of the
subcontinent. West is Gujarat, Sind,
Balojasthan and east
is east of Bengal we have these states
right Nagal, Manipur, Misaram etc. So
it's clearly the far east of India just
like Balojasthan is the far west of
India. It's not the northeast.
How is it north? It's the east.
Northeast would be Nepal possibly.
So this should be called the far east of
India. So why is it called the northeast
of India? Shall I explain why it's
called the northeast of India? The
British occupiers of India, they first
colon established colonies in what is
now Bengal.
Okay?
They first colonized India from Bengal.
So situated in Bengal from if you are
sitting in Bengal then to the northeast
of Bengal you have these states. So
sitting in Kolkata or wherever from
there this place was the northeast of
Bengal. That makes sense because from
Bengal geographically northeast is this
entire region.
But eventually the British took over the
whole of India.
But they had written about these states
as the northeast because they were at
that time situated in Bengal. But the
Indian historians, mentally colonized
morons, I would say continued calling
the far east of India the northeast of
India. And even today without even
bothering to understand why it was once
called northeast, our historians, our
politicians, our leaders, our our
citizens, they keep calling it
northeast, northeast of India.
It is the far east of India. It's a
British colonial hangover that that's
why we call it the northeast because the
British were initially based only in
Bengal. From there it was in the
northeastern direction.
We are so mentally colonized. We just
blindly keep doing things without
understanding why these names and terms
exist in the first place. We Indians
don't think at all. Right? The the
switch has been turned off. The thinking
switch. The the switch that asks
questions if someone if this place is
called the northeast, why is it called
the northeast? Because it is not in the
north. It's simply the far east. But no,
we will blindly keep on paring whatever
our textbooks and teachers told us,
taught us and that's it. We don't think
mentally lobtomized. That's what we are.
All right.
Shub says why does why do north Indians
UP and Bihar seem more dassinated from
their ancestral culture and way of life
as compared to South India, Bengal,
Maharashtra?
The longer you are under foreign
occupation and under foreign brutality,
the more dassinated you're going to be.
Because the foreigners, the Turks tried
to eradicate our culture. They tried to
impose their foreign religion and
culture on us, didn't they? And they
succeeded to some extent. They destroyed
all of our temples. That's why you have
great temples in southern India. But no
great temple that is standing intact in
northern India.
In northern India, you were under Turk
rule for centuries and Gandhar was the
longest under Turkish rule which is what
now it is completely
um converted.
The same thing eventually happened in
Kashmir and various parts of northern
India, Punjab, Hana,
um
whatever else it was these parts of
India were for for several centuries
under Turk rule. So the Turk culture,
the Muggal culture, it seeped into our
our culture in various ways.
Why do you have weddings in the night in
North India? In northern India because
the Turks practiced something called
bride kidnapping which I've spoken about
in Anatolia.
They would kidnap young girls who had
just got married on their wedding night
or wedding day. And so so it was it was
necessary to do weddings in a way that
the the Turks would not notice. That's
why you had to do nics in the middle of
the night and that culture is now our
culture apparently. It was not our
original culture. See
um so the longer you are under foreign
brutality, oppression, occupation,
the more deassinated you you're going to
be. And that's why we have the situation
that we have.
Okay, let's uh Okay. Bascar Bandit says,
"When did the idea of white skin being
superior actually start or originate?
Was it from the Anglo-Saxon British
Empire?
Do we see traces of this earlier in
Roman Empire or even before that?"
Thank you, sir.
This notion of white skin being
superior,
it dates back only about 230 years.
So the Europeans became dominant in the
past 500 years and eventually after a
couple of centuries to three centuries
they started believing that their skin
tone is racially superior and anybody
who has the skin tone associated with
the Europeans is naturally superior to
other people because they became so
dominant because of a variety of
reasons. During the Roman times or Greek
times was white skin supposedly
superior? The Greeks fought the Persians
for centuries. Did the Greeks believe
that the Persians were inferior to them
because the Persians had darker skin
than than the Greeks? No.
Did Alexander believe that the Indians
were inferior to him because Indians had
darker skin? No. No such thing.
Absolutely nothing. Right.
um Roman Empire. The Romans, the
original Romans, not today's Italians,
the original Romans had dark hair and
dark eyes
[clears throat] and they had darker skin
compared to the Nordic people and the
Celtic peoples.
Okay. Then you have the conquest of Gaul
and the conquest of various other parts
of Europe.
When this happens, the Romans start
start bringing in large numbers of
slaves from these parts of Europe which
they had subjugated.
So when you bring in slaves, women
slaves, let's say, from the Celtic parts
of Europe etc., most of those women and
people will have blonde hair and those
were enslaved. And when you when the
Romans enslaved women, they did all
kinds of terrible things to them because
slaves are just property, right?
So, so the Romans, you know, they passed
a law,
what was the law? All prostitutes in
Rome had to either wear a blonde wig or
to dye their hair blonde because Roman
women could not be prostitutes or if
they had to be prostitutes they had to
dye their head hair blonde or wear a
blonde wig because blonde hair was
um a mark of the non-Romans, the white
people. The Romans were they had darker
skin tones than the than the uh northern
Europeans. the Kelts.
So, did the Romans believe that the
Northern Europeans who had whiter skin
than them and blonde hair, blue eyes, do
did the Romans think that that was
superior to them? No. They believed
Romans were superior to the white
people, to the whiter people. You see,
and you can fact check whatever I've
just said. Check it out, Google it or
whatever it.
So the idea of white skin skin being
superior originated pretty recently
maybe two- 300 years the past two 300
years the Irish were discriminated
against for a very long time in North
America the Irish have whiter skin than
the British
right but they were discriminated
against they were considered non-white
or or or racially inferior for a long
time and to get rid of that the Irish
had to be super racist against the
blacks and that's how they were accepted
as whites. Long story, pretty pretty
dark stories here. So the the entire
thing of white skin being superior, it
it it emerges in the past two or 300
years roughly.
Krishna Krishna of the Suridum
Netherlands says after finding the
Sonali chariot when are we going to find
the Kuruketra chariots?
So we have discovered chariot a chariot
or chariots at least one chariot in
Sonali. What about Kuruketra?
Well I suppose there could be chariots
buried in the Kurukhetra region.
But how will we find those chariots
if we don't do an archaeological dig in
Kurukhetra?
What about Indrata? Indrata is in Delhi.
But do we do anything there? Has any
archaeological expedition or dig or
project happened there? No.
That's the problem in India. Our entire
history is buried under the ground
and the ASI doesn't bother to do a thing
about it.
I mean, if you look at the the paleo
channel, the dry riverbed of the
Saraspati,
along the the banks of the dry riverbed,
you have at least 2,000 known but
unexplored archaeological sites.
When are we going to start exploring
those? Imagine the amount of new
information that will emerge if you do
that. We have Raki Guri. We have a
couple of sites Kalib Bangan Rakari
Davir Loal four five places that we keep
on talking about talking about talking
about what about Dara which is lying
offshore under the ocean when are we
going to start exploring that
archaeologically in a serious way when
when do we even care I mean we care we
people but what is the government doing
what is the ASI doing I'm not sure what
so you know unless
This is taken up in a serious manner,
nothing's going to be found. Sonali was
an accident. We just stumbled upon the
chariot. If we start looking properly
using various, you know, modern
technologies like LAR and whatnot, so
much more will emerge.
But uh why waste money on that when you
can use money somewhere else?
Okay.
Um let's take one a couple more
questions. Let's let's take this one.
Shoua says, "Ni restoration in 1868
rejected the Dharmic way of life and
made Japan move towards westernization
and the result was absolutely horrific."
Yes, we know Japanese soldiers became
absolutely barbaric, brutal. We know
that. Yes, India is also going forward
in the same direction gradually. What
are my thoughts?
Well, we aren't wholesale rejecting
Indian culture the way the major
restoration did. See the major
restoration was brutal in so many
different ways. Japan for a thousand
years was a vegetarian society. The
samuris, the warriors, the chhatrias of
Japan, they were also vegetarian but
they ate fish, seafood like the people
of Manipur or the people of Bengal today
who claimed to be vegetarian but they
can eat fish. So fish was like
vegetarian food for them. So the
samurai, the great warriors were almost
vegetarian but they ate fish. And the
rest of the people of Japan, they were
completely vegetarian.
Cow slaughter was taboo.
So what did the Maji restoration do? The
bureaucrats who carried out the Maji
restoration, the coup, they made the
king of Japan, the Maji emperor consume
beef
so that it is no longer a taboo. If the
god emperor does it, the people can do
it. And that's the kind of thing it was.
So in India we don't have that extreme
level of very rapid very radical
cultural extermination of our culture.
That's not happening. It's happening
gradually.
Uh but if it continues in the direction
we also may go in the along similar
paths. Who knows? Yeah. Because we are
today gradually dassinating ourselves.
The the education system dassinates
Indians. Uh the textbooks, the teachers,
they do that. The media does it. The
news the entertainment industry does it.
Government does it in a variety of
indirect ways knowingly or unknowingly
you know so eventually we will also go
in the direction which is terrible if it
happens. So I hope we change course we
course correct and we return to our
civilizational roots. That's what needs
to happen ideally.
Sunmoon08 says why don't we have our own
type of beauty standards like in ancient
times having mustache was a form of
masculinity now it's considered
unhygienic because of the current Indian
beauty standards are Korean K-pop
standards [laughter]
we always follow the west in our or
other countries see India I keep
referring to India as a civilization
right but a civilization one of the
characteristics it has is that it's a
net exporter of culture today India is a
wholesale importer of culture because of
the inferiority complex we have been
saddled with or people have been saddled
with and uh that sort of thing. So we
are now an importer of culture. We copy
trends that come from the west or from
the east or whatever. K-pop. What is
K-pop?
I don't get it. You don't even
understand the language.
So
Indians are dassinated. Indians have
this inferiority complex. massive
infrared complex which is why Indians
want to absorb and and ape like monkeys
everything that comes from abroad from
any nation that is you know financially
more prosperous than ours.
So it's a terrible thing right we should
have our own standards we should once
again become a net exporter of culture
but for that we have to become more
prosperous and the government needs to
reinvest reinvest in Indian culture and
civilization which it is not doing right
now so that's the deal and let's take
one last question
by swapnil
how did the resettlement of freed
African-American and Caribbean slaves
shape the founding and development of
Liberia and Sierra Leon in the 19th
century Okay, first of all, what part of
the world is this? Let us figure it out.
Let's go to the map. So, we're talking
about western
Africa, southwestern Africa. Okay,
so we have this small nation here called
Sierra Leon with whose capital is
Freetown.
And we have this nation called Liberia
which is to the east of Sierra Leon
whose capital is Monrovia or the largest
city is Monrovia. Now what is the deal
with these two nations Liberia and
Sierra Leon?
So Sierra Leon was founded
by freed slaves from the Caribbean
region
in the
late 18th century and Liberia was
founded by freed slaves from the United
States in the early 19th century.
And
so what happened? What was the outcome
of this?
So in both nations, the people who
migrated, the freed slaves who came from
the Caribbean in the case of Sri Leon
and the freed slaves who came from the
United States in the case of Liberia,
these people who came from North America
and the Caribbean, they became the
dominant societ, the dominant community
in these two countries. But these two
countries had natives who lived there.
those were completely sidelined and
marginalized and oppressed.
So the freed slaves come and oppress and
kind of enslave the natives of the land.
Imagine that. Yeah.
So what were the consequences of this?
Eventually disaster. So in Liberia you
had this
I forget the name of the political party
which was the political party of the
freed slaves. They dominated Liberia
until about 1980 when there was a coup
and a gentleman, a fine gentleman called
Samuel Doe assassinated uh William
Tolbert or whoever his name was and
became the dictator of Liberia
and then
about 8 nine years ago he was himself
assassinated in a very nasty way by
someone called Charles Taylor. So Samuel
Doe was a native who assassinated one of
the descendants of the free freed slaves
and he himself was assassinated in a
very brutal way by somebody called
Charles Taylor and this led to a civil
war which spilled over into Srira Leon
and uh this went on for years and it's
been a pretty horrific period of time
and I would highly recommend do not
search for images of the Liberian civil
war and Srira Leon civil for on Google
images. Do not search for that.
Horrific.
Um, so the resettlement of these freed
African-American and Caribbean slaves,
it destabilized
the part of Africa where they were
settled because they themselves became
the oppressors. They were like we are
superior. we came from North America or
wherever and we are Christians and we
are European in in values and we are
better than you black Africans because
we have a some amount of white blood
perhaps that sort of thing. Imagine
that. So it destabilized these places
and the outcome of that has been
absolute horror and these are some of
the poorest countries in the world.
Yeah. So it did not work out very well
this experiment.
Okay, that brings me to the to the end
of today's questions. Now, let's take a
few questions from the live chat. All
right, let us do that. Um, what do we
have? What do we have? Um,
do we have any questions?
Sukun Verer says, can you tell us about
the Kash temple at Laura? How big of an
engineer achievement it was for ancient
Indians? I am not any kind of expert in
this, so I can't say. Oh, I see that we
have some super chats. So, about the
Kash temple, I am not aware of the
details. I am aware of the the fact that
it's a it's a monolithic temple, a
rocket temple carved out of a single
hill or mountain and it must have taken
an incredible amount of time and effort
and expenditure to to to make it. But I
don't know about the specifications in
detail.
We have supercharged. Please first of
all stop taking super chats because I
have
run past the 2our limit. Okay. Basker
Bandit says
when did the idea of whites king being
superior start? I just took this
question a while ago. So there we have
it.
Anyway, thank you for the question.
Basar Bandit once again says the west is
hellbent on showing Shri Chingghis Khan
as a barbarian. If Alexander as if
Alexander and Alexander the Greek was
very civilized in his travels, is it
only because they can't digest somebody
in the east had a bigger emperor empire?
Yes, of course. See, today the west
dominates the world and they seek to
downplay the achievements of all
non-western peoples, kingdoms, cultures,
civilizations, empires, especially
non-white
entities. Changing Khan one man
conquered half the known world of his
time. He conquered half of Eurasia. He
himself did not conquer half of Eurasia.
Maybe maybe at least more than a third
of Eurasia. But eventually the Mongol
Empire encompassed half of Eurasia
essentially right and was Chingghistan
by India. So he is portrayed as a great
mass murderer or whatever. If you
compare Chingishan with Tim Theimore, if
you look at the the amount of land
Chingishan conquered and the alleged
death toll and if you divide the death
toll by the land in square kilometers,
then Chingish Khan killed way less
people per square kilome than kilometer
than Timour. But nobody says that about
Timur and I'm not sure about Alexander.
We don't even know how many people he
killed. He was pretty brutal and
extremely cruel and I've spoken about
this in in detail what he did in entire
what he did in thieves absolute brutal
cruel behavior and what he did in India
you know in western India he he burned
entire villages alive
so much more Alexander was a was a
barbarian and he he was motivated by
personal glory he was a robber on a vast
scale that's what Alexander was Jinger
Khan was Not that. So why is the west
hellbent on showing Chingghist Khan like
this? Because he was not white. Cuz he
was not Christian. You see that's why
MK says enlighten us about the theft of
Indian art, fashion, textiles, beauty,
handiccrafts, mathematics,
pharmaceuticals, pharmacological
toxicology etc. by the west.
Why are soul vultures relatively less
successful in north? How many questions
do you have sir? Look, I have discussed
this in so many episodes
and I took the question of the
plagiarism of the Chinese and the west
today as well. So I have kind of covered
this uh but you have given so many
different point data points Indian art,
fashion, textiles, beauty, handiccrafts
and so on. It will take like at least an
hour to discuss this this in detail. But
yeah, it all of that has been stolen,
plagiarized, absorbed, digested and it
is now being repackaged as western
inventions. For example, we have
something called pranayam. Now they call
it cardiac coherence breathing as if
they invented this thing. They came up
with this new thing.
There is
you know Indian sadhus Indian Indian
sadhus etc. They they they have been
known for thousands of years to spend
years in the Himalayas wearing very
little clothing and they can take the
cold of the Himalayas. Right. Today
there's this guy called Vimhof who has
taken that cold exposure thing from our
sadhus and he's also taken the
kapalabati or bastria
um methodology from pranayam and he's
combined that into the vimhof method. It
is nothing but the vimhof method of
cultural theft. So there are so many
examples of this. The Chinese are also
doing it and one can discuss this in
great detail. [clears throat]
Uh WBR says historically has any
currency been as dominant as the US
dollar aside from gold? What are the
reasons for the dominance of a
particular currency in the world? No
currency has been globally as dominant
as the US dollar beside aside from gold.
What are the reasons for the dominance
of the US dollar? The US's military
might and global power projection
capabilities. Okay. They can intervene
militarily anywhere on the surface of
the planet at about 60 minutes notice.
and they have more than 700 800 extr
territorial military bases all across
the world. When they have that sort of
global power production capability and
the world's strongest military,
they can use that to enforce the US
dollar as the global reserve currency
and that's why it is the case.
CS19J Hint says, I've been watching your
show for a very long time. My question
is why are people in north
morphologically different than people in
south India even though the genetics are
almost almost the same? Genetics almost
the same people in northern India look
kind of different from people in
southern southern India. Let me give you
a very simple
contrasting example. Imran Khan the
Pakistani cricketer who's in jail now
prime minister and Mutya Muridan the Sri
Lankan cricketer Tamil cricketer they
will have very similar genetics but they
look very different. Why is that?
Because see today we have to look at the
world not from today's lens. Today if I
want to go from Tamil Nadu to Delhi or
or Kabul, I can do that in 4 hours, take
a flight and go there. So we imagine
that we can travel very easily all
across India. And why are people
different?
In the past, people had to travel by
foot. to travel from southern India to
Kabul Gandhar would take several
I don't know a couple of years
right
and that's only in the past maybe 5
10,000 years before that the the
subcontinent was full of forests and
people were isolated wherever they were
so people who lived in southern India
would have communication contacts to
some extent with the rest of rest of
India in some way but they would not
travel migrate intermar all of that so
people who lived in different parts of
India they because of the different
climates because of the different amount
of sun exposure they they developed
different different skin tones and so
much more and that's why morphologically
they are different because this was the
case for thousands of years maybe tens
of thousands of years the people of the
Yamuna Valley Ganga Valley who lived
there 30,000 years ago their descendants
would stay there most likely for another
another 10 2000 thousand years without
going elsewhere because it was so
fertile so you don't need to go
elsewhere and because there are forests
everywhere, jungles with tigers, you had
hundreds of thousands of tigers in India
and bears and and pythons and whatnot.
You don't travel, you stay where you
are.
So even though we all originated from
the same population group, we spread
across the subcontinent and for tens of
thousands of years different population
groups um evolved in different ways and
that's why we have this difference in
morphology.
James
James says you could send a thousand
10,000 Europeans in Antarctica and after
100 years there would be people trying
to seek asylum. You need class look at
Australia, etc.
Australia is a great case study of
European colonization. It is said that
you know you send Europeans to a certain
part of the world for 100 years and they
will completely transform it. They will
turn a barren place into a first world
country. Take the example of Australia
or the United States or Canada or any of
these countries that the Europeans
colonized. Well, I'll tell you what.
To do that in Australia, they first had
to genocide the natives. They had to
classify the natives as flora and fauna.
Yeah. Would you like me to show you
something, James? James, first of all, I
appreciate you. Let me repeat that.
Okay. So,
um, Australian
Abori jeans
um in chains.
So, check this out. [snorts]
Um, they won't show it. Why? Why is this
safe search nonsense on view image?
Check it out.
Check it out. Check it out.
See, this is how they they treated
Australians, the natives. They were
treated like animals. You had to first
eradicate the natives, marginalize them,
diminish their population, push them to
the fringes, and then you could take
over the nice parts of Australia and
build cities there. When it comes to the
Americas, they had to wipe out a 100
million natives to build this beautiful
these beautiful countries, a country
built on the genocide of the natives and
the slavery of the Africans. So yes,
once you do that, once you ethnically
cleanse your land, the land you have you
have occupied, then you can
build a first world country over the
bones of the dead, I suppose.
Right, James? Thank you. Appreciate you.
MK says, "Who were more brutal,
barbaric, Arabs or Turks?" Look, how do
you quantify
brutality?
The Turks learned it from the Arabs. I
would say the original Arabs. [laughter]
I would say both were in different ways,
kind of equally brutal in different
ways.
For us, it's the Turks. For the
Iranians, it's it's the Turks more than
the Arabs. But the Arabs were the first
to to brutalize the Persians, weren't
they? So different, but similar. Kevin
says, "Keep up the great work, Abij. God
bless. Much love." Thank you so much,
Kevin. Thank you so much. God bless you
too as well. Thank you so much for your
support.
Uh Akil Sai says I don't like what the
cast system has turned out to be. I want
to know but I want to know more about Si
and Shai was pori or ajat. Look sir, I
have no idea. Um
I I don't know about the si or or
suraseni etc. Lineages
uh there are so many of these there are
tens of thousands of lineages in India.
all ancient lineages going back all the
way to the Vic times, right? And it was
not the cast system, it was the Jati
Vera system. And today the cast system
has become this oppressive thing.
But this was institutionalized by the
British
and the government of India after 47
continued this nonsense. If cast system
is so bad, why don't you simply abolish
cast? Abolish all cast divisions. Don't
give reservations on the basis of cast.
Right? Give reservations on the basis of
financial status. Isn't that simple?
But the politicians they benefit from
the reservations and the cast politics.
Right? You have to completely abolish
cast if you really believe in that. So
my point is we had a verna system which
was incredibly complex and the British
could not understand it because they did
not have the brains for that. So they
decided to divide India into four casts
and they forced Indians to choose what
cast you are part of that sort of thing.
But I don't know about whether porus was
a sini or a jat si I mean jat the term
jat did not exist
during the time of porus
right it's like it's like saying that
Buddha was Nepali Nepal the concept of
Nepal did not exist 2 and a half
thousand years ago so please understand
that the past was a different time you
cannot force you cannot retrofit today's
classifications into the past you can't
Amisha says Indian kings wear Indian
king wear is sign of royalty turbans or
crown
uh the the concept of crowns I I don't
think it's it's native to India
turbans
I don't think it's a sign of royalty
either
lots of different jatiwers wear turbans
so it's not a sign of royalty the turban
and crowns were never part of Indian
culture as far as I understand it's a
western thing so what did Indian kings
have as a sign of royalty
[laughter]
I suppose
they would carry weapons but the katrias
carry weapons right
yeah that's a great question I'm not
sure what was a sign of royalty
the I don't think the crown was an
Indian thing turbans lots Different
groups of people wear turbons. There
must have been something. But we have
lost the records of those times, right?
What did Chandra Gupta Moria wear that
others did not wear? I'm not sure. If
you look at the coinage of Kaneshka, he
doesn't wear a crown.
I suppose you were king because you were
king and you do not have to wear
something special to to to tell the
people that I am superior to you. And
your soldiers and your power that that
made you superior and that made you the
ruler. And you were not someone who
ruled, you were someone who served. That
was the dharmic way of ruling. Right?
UMX glow haha says maybe Indians crave
other cultures because Bollywood which
is apparently supposed to be our culture
is terrible propaganda. What's the
solution? You see what passes is Indian
culture. Today if you look at if you
look at Bollywood they think that Indian
culture is Bollywood dance
Bollywood dance is not Indian culture it
is I don't have a polite word to term
what Bollywood dance is Bollywood music
sounds sometimes more
west Asian middle eastern than Indian
music
um so Bollywood has has played a big
role in in uh brainwashing Indians and
Indians for the longest time were
starved of entertainment. So they just
absorbed whatever nonsense comes from
Bollywood and today Indians play these
Bollywood songs even during festivals.
What is the solution? The solution is
the democratization of of culture.
Today you can
see if you're a singer, if you're a
musician, if you're an artist, you don't
need a record label. You don't need a
big producer to put your work in front
of the people of India, right? Or the
world. You can simply make a YouTube
video of your of your song or or
whatever it is that you're doing. And I
think that is going to be the solution.
But is it too late? Are all Indian
artists already infected with this mind
virus? I'm not sure.
The solution is the democratization
democratization of of of
content creation.
Uh so that could be a solution but I
it's possible that it's already too late
because most Indian
creators, artists etc are are
brainwashed. They have been infected
with this with with this Bollywood
virus. But I think there is still hope
and hopefully that that will be the
solution. Okay. Um,
go. When is another episode of Delulu
Indians believe in
coming?
Delusions Indians believe in coming.
Would you like one? I could make an
extended version of that. Perhaps I
could do that. Let me know. All right,
that brings me to the end of today's
live stream. Thank you very much. This
was great fun as always.
Um
let's see
uh let's take one last question. Nirj
this says why does Sanskrit have so many
words for the same things like surya
ravi etc. What was the reason for this?
Was this just for poetic purposes? It's
because Sanskrit is so old.
There must be a 100 different words for
snow in Sanskrit. There must be 100
words for love
in Sanskrit. Vatalia, sna, pre just
three I can think of. There must be so
many more. Sanskrit is so old that it
has so many synonyms. For example, we
have the word ratri for night. But an
older word for the same ratri in the
Vedas is nakta.
Nakta. That's the older word for
night. Nakta in Vic Sanskrit nakta in
German night in English.
So it's the world's oldest language that
we know of and it's been around for
thousands and thousands of years. That's
why we have so Nisha Mahita says Nisha.
Thank you ma'am. Great example Nisha.
So it's so old and that's why we have so
many synonyms. All right people, thank
you so much for the questions. I really
enjoyed this. I got you all asked so
many great questions in the comments. I
could not take them all but keep keep
doing it. Why are we doing this these
these history live streams? Because
history is the foundation of the world.
We have to understand history if you
want to understand the way the world is
and the direction in which it is going.
History the study of history shows us
the patterns and regularities in
history. History is cyclical. So to
understand today, we have to study
history and that's why I keep doing
these history live streams. Thank you so
much for the questions, for your
viewership, for everything. And tomorrow
we're going to have a geopolitics live
stream, a super chat live stream. I look
forward to seeing you there. Thank you
so much. Keep asking questions, keep
learning, keep learning, and keep
raising your standards. I'll see you
tomorrow. Thank you. bye-bye.